<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jamesbaldwin on Noam&#39;s Website About Software</title>
    <link>http://noamswebsite.com/rtags/jamesbaldwin/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jamesbaldwin on Noam&#39;s Website About Software</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://noamswebsite.com/rtags/jamesbaldwin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>James Baldwin</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/james_baldwin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/james_baldwin/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;spoken-video&#34;&gt;Spoken / Video&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buckley Debate At Cambridge&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/oFeoS41xe7w&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Baldwin&amp;rsquo;s Nigger&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/DeFpzp1pBjc&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Debate With Malcolm X (Audio Only (Can anyone find the full recording? It cuts out at the end.))&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-JIp9_IIV3s&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sentimentality&#34;&gt;Sentimentality&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sentimentality, the ostentatious parading of excessive and spurious emotion,
is the mark of dishonesty, the inability to feel; the wet eyes of the
sentimentalist betray his aversion to experience, his fear of life, his arid
heart; and it is always, therefore, the signal of secret and violent
inhumanity, the mark of cruelty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;inferiority&#34;&gt;Inferiority&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is the peculiar triumph of society &amp;ndash; and its loss &amp;ndash; that it is able to
convince those people of whom it has given inferior status of the reality of
this decree; it has the force and the weapons to translated its dictum into
fact, so that the allegedly inferior are actually made so, in so far as the
societal realities are concerned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There exists among the intolerable degraded, the perverse and powerful desire
to force into the arena of the actual those fantastic crimes of which they
have been accused, achieving their vengeance and their own destruction
through making the nightmare real.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;american-moral-contradictions&#34;&gt;American Moral Contradictions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Americans, unhappily, have the most remarkable ability to alchemize all
bitter truths into an innocuous but piquant confection and to transform their
moral contradictions, or public discussion of such contradictions, into a
proud decoration, such as are given for heroism on the field of battle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;outsider-insider-dichotomy&#34;&gt;Outsider / Insider Dichotomy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Negroes are Americans and their destiny is the country’s destiny. They have
no other experience besides their experience on this continent and it is an
experience which cannot be rejected, which yet remains to be embraced. [&amp;hellip;]
What most significantly fails to be illuminated here is the paradoxical
adjustment which is perpetually made, the Negro being compelled to accept the
fact that this dark and dangerous and unloved stranger is part of himself
forever. [It is] this necessary ability to contain and even, in the most
honorable sense of the word, to exploit the “nigger,” which lends Negro life
its high element of the ironic and which causes the most well-meaning of
their American critics to make such exhilarating errors when attempting to
understand them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;struggle&#34;&gt;Struggle&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not one of the people who believe that oppression imbues a people with wisdom or insight or sweet charity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;jewish-black-relations&#34;&gt;Jewish-Black Relations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a subterranean assumption that the Jew should “know better,” that he
has suffered enough himself to know what suffering means. [&amp;hellip;] The Jew, by
the nature of his own precarious position, has failed to vindicate this
faith. Jews, like Negroes, must use every possible weapon in order to be
accepted, and must try to cover their vulnerability by a frenzied adoption of
the customs of the country; and the nation’s treatment of Negroes is
unquestionably a custom. The Jew has been taught—and, too often, accepts—the
legend of Negro inferiority; and the Negro, on the other hand, has found
nothing in his experience with Jews to counteract the legend of Semitic
greed. Here the American white Gentile has two legends serving him at once:
he has divided these minorities and he rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But just as a society must have a scapegoat, so hatred must have a symbol. Georgia has the Negro and Harlem has the Jew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>