<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Social on Noam&#39;s Website About Software</title>
    <link>http://noamswebsite.com/rtags/social/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Social on Noam&#39;s Website About Software</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://noamswebsite.com/rtags/social/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Epictetus</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/epictetus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/epictetus/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;enchiridion&#34;&gt;Enchiridion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;x&#34;&gt;X&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the occasion of every accident (event) that befalls you, remember to turn
to yourself and inquire what power you have for turning it to use. If you see
a fair man or a fair woman, you will find that the power to resist is
temperance (continence). If labour (pain) be presented to you, you will find
that it is endurance. If it be abusive words, you will find it to be
patience. And if you have been thus formed to the (proper) habit, the
appearances will not carry you along with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;xi&#34;&gt;XI&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never say about any thing, I have lost it, but say I have restored it. Is
your child dead? It has been restored. Is your wife dead? She has been
restored. Has your estate been taken from you? Has not then this also been
restored? But he who has taken it from me is a bad man. But what is it to
you, by whose hands the giver demanded it back? So long as he may allow you,
take care of it as a thing which belongs to another, as travellers do with
their inn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;xvii&#34;&gt;XVII&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember that thou art an actor in a play, of such a kind as the teacher
(author) may choose; if short, of a short one; if long, of a long one: if he
wishes you to act the part of a poor man, see that you act the part
naturally; if the part of a lame man, of a magistrate, of a private person,
(do the same). For this is your duty, to act well the part that is given to
you; but to select the part, belongs to another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;xxi&#34;&gt;XXI&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let death and exile and every other thing which appears dreadful be daily
before your eyes; but most of all death: and you will never think of any
thing mean nor will you desire any thing extravagantly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;xxiii&#34;&gt;XXIII&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a man has reported to you, that a certain person speaks ill of you, do not
make any defence to what has been told you: but reply, The man did
not know the rest of my faults, for he would not have mentioned these only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;xxxv&#34;&gt;XXXV&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you have decided that a thing ought to be done and are doing it, never
avoid being seen doing it, though the many shall form an unfavourable opinion
about it. For if it is not right to do it, avoid doing the thing; but if it
is right, why are you afraid of those who shall find fault wrongly?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;xvii-1&#34;&gt;XVII&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have assumed a character above your strength, you have both acted in
this matter in an unbecoming way, and you have neglected that which you might
have fulfilled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;xliii&#34;&gt;XLIII&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every thing has two handles, the one by which it may be borne, the other by
which it may not. If your brother acts unjustly, do not lay hold of the act
by that handle wherein he acts unjustly, for this is the handle which cannot
be borne: but lay hold of the other, that he is your brother, that he was
nurtured with you, and you will lay hold of the thing by that handle by which
it can be borne.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;xlvi&#34;&gt;XLVI&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On no occasion call yourself a philosopher, and do not speak much among the
uninstructed about theorems (philosophical rules, precepts): but do that
which follows from them. For example at a banquet do not say how a man ought
to eat, but eat as you ought to eat. For remember that in this way Socrates
also altogether avoided ostentation: persons used to come to him and ask to
be recommended by him to philosophers, and he used to take them to
philosophers: so easily did he submit to being overlooked. Accordingly if any
conversation should arise among uninstructed persons about any theorem,
generally be silent; for there is great danger that you will immediately
vomit up what you have not digested. And when a man shall say to you, that
you know nothing, and you are not vexed, then be sure that you have begun the
work (of philosophy). For even sheep do not vomit up their grass and show to
the shepherds how much they have eaten; but when they have internally
digested the pasture, they produce externally wool and milk. Do you also show
not your theorems to the uninstructed, but show the acts which come from
their digestion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;xlviii&#34;&gt;XLVIII&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The condition and characteristic of an uninstructed person is this: he never
expects from himself profit (advantage) nor harm, but from externals. The
condition and characteristic of a philosopher is this: he expects all
advantage and all harm from himself. The signs (marks) of one who is making
progress are these: he censures no man, he praises no man, he blames no man,
he accuses no man, he says nothing about himself as if he were somebody or
knew something; when he is impeded at all or hindered, he blames himself: if
a man praises him, he ridicules the praiser to himself: if a man censures
him, he makes no defence: he goes about like weak persons, being careful not
to move any of the things which are placed, before they are firmly fixed: he
removes all desire from himself, and he transfers aversion
(ἔκκλισιν)&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; to those things only of the things within our power
which are contrary to nature: he employs a moderate movement towards every
thing: whether he is considered foolish or ignorant, he cares not: and in a
word he watches himself as if he were an enemy and lying in ambush.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;pre&gt;
1) Turning of one&amp;rsquo;s course, deflexion.
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hannah Arendt</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/hannah_arendt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/hannah_arendt/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;understanding&#34;&gt;Understanding&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I am working, I am not interested in how my work might affect people.
[And when I am finished] I am finished. What is important to me is to
understand. For me, writing is a matter of seeking this understanding …
certain things get formulated. […] What is important to me is the process of
thought itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You ask about the effects of my work on others. If I may wax ironical, that is
a masculine question. Men always want to be terribly influential, but I see
that as somewhat external. Do I imagine myself being influential? No. I want
to understand. And if others understand — in the same sense that I have
understood — that gives me a sense of satisfaction, like feeling at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;marginalization&#34;&gt;Marginalization&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m more than ever of the opinion that a decent human existence is possible
today only on the fringes of society, where one then runs the risk of starving
or being stoned to death. In these circumstances, a sense of humor is a great
help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fundamental deprivation of human rights is manifested first and above all
in the deprivation of a place in the world which makes opinions significant
and actions effective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a human being loses political status. [&amp;hellip;] It seems that a man who is
nothing but a man has lost the very qualities which make it possible for other
people to treat him as a fellow-man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is quite conceivable, and even within the realm of practical political
possibilities, that one fine day a highly organized and mechanized humanity
will conclude quite democratically &amp;ndash; namely by majority decision &amp;ndash; that for
humanity as a whole it would be better to liquidate certain parts thereof.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;agency&#34;&gt;Agency&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It just doesn’t look good when a woman gives orders. She should try not to get
herself into such situations if she wants to remain feminine. Whether I am
right about this I do not know. I myself have lived in accordance to this more
or less unconsciously — or let us rather say, more or less consciously. The
problem itself played no role for me personally. To put it very simply, I have
always done what I liked to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often misquoted by critics. Whether Hannah lived in a society that deemed her
worthy or capable of pursuing her interests was irrelevant. This society and its
opinions were a thing that existed beyond the scope of her personal influence.
She neither questioned her worthiness nor waited for permission. She simply
acted. She asserted control of the only social agent over which she had control:
herself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of humanity, when purged of all sentimentality, has the very serious
consequence that in one form or another men must assume responsibility for all
crimes committed by men and that all nations share the onus of evil committed
by all others. Shame at being a human being is the purely individual and still
non-political expression of this insight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>James Baldwin</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/james_baldwin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/james_baldwin/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;spoken&#34;&gt;Spoken&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;buckley-debate-at-cambridge&#34;&gt;Buckley Debate At Cambridge&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/oFeoS41xe7w&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;baldwin-s-nigger&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Baldwin&amp;rsquo;s Nigger&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ryuAW_gnjYQ&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;debate-with-malcolm-x-audio-only&#34;&gt;Debate With Malcolm X (Audio Only)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Can anyone find the full recording? It cuts out at the end.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-JIp9_IIV3s&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John Stuart Mill</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/john_stuart_mill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/john_stuart_mill/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;on-freedom-of-speech&#34;&gt;On Freedom Of Speech&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have now recognised the necessity to the mental well-being of mankind (on
which all their other well-being depends) of freedom of opinion, and freedom
of the expression of opinion, on four distinct grounds; which we will now
briefly recapitulate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, if any opinion is compelled to silence, that opinion may, for aught we
can certainly know, be true. To deny this is to assume our own infallibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, though the silenced opinion be an error, it may, and very commonly
does, contain a portion of truth; and since the general or prevailing opinion
on any subject is rarely or never the whole truth, it is only by the collision
of adverse opinions that the remainder of the truth has any chance of being
supplied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thirdly, even if the received opinion be not only true, but the whole truth;
unless it is suffered to be, and actually is, vigorously and earnestly
contested, it will, by most of those who receive it, be held in the manner of
a prejudice, with little comprehension or feeling of its rational grounds. And
not only this, but, fourthly, the meaning of the doctrine itself will be in
danger of being lost, or enfeebled, and deprived of its vital effect on the
character and conduct: the dogma becoming a mere formal profession,
inefficacious for good, but cumbering the ground, and preventing the growth of
any real and heartfelt conviction, from reason or personal experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweep</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/sweep/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/sweep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was on my regular afternoon bike ride when I noticed a crowd of people
sweeping the walkways. I leaned my bike on a tree and  went to the first man and
asked &amp;ldquo;Why do you sweep?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I sweep because I resign,&amp;rdquo; he said to me.&amp;ldquo;I used to go blue in the face with
how dirty these streets were. But it was no use, they paid no attention, and I
would go mad each day when upon arriving I would dirty my carpet. I swear I was
losing my mind. I would shout and complain and nobody did a damn thing. Finally
I resigned to the situation. And I was struck by a notion, that only one thing
was within my reach to do, and I got myself this broom and since then I keep my
head down and sweep.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;And what if another walks on your path and muddies it again?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Then I sweep.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thanked the man and went on to the next one and asked &amp;ldquo;Why do you sweep?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I sweep because someone has to. I always suspected these streets were not as
clean as they could be, but none would have it,&amp;rdquo; he answered, then looked both
ways to check if anyone was eavesdropping before adding &amp;ldquo;downright dirty,
actually &amp;ndash; and then one day I saw that man over there sweeping. So I got a
broom and started sweeping too.&amp;rdquo; He paused for a moment, tired, then looked at
me again with pride: &amp;ldquo;Look how clean my walkway is!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving on, I asked another group of people, further down the crowd why they
swept: &amp;ldquo;Well, we sweep because it&amp;rsquo;s proper,&amp;rdquo; answered one. &amp;ldquo;We saw those over
there doing it, and it seemed like a good enough thing to do to join in. The
streets are much cleaner now, don&amp;rsquo;t you see?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked further into the crowd, some were sweeping more vigorously than others,
but even the lazy ones stood with brooms in their hands and talked of how much
they loved to sweep, and again I asked one &amp;ldquo;Why do you sweep?&amp;rdquo; and he said &amp;ldquo;We
sweep because everyone sweeps. How else do you think these streets would stay so
clean?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And a little further down, I asked again and one said to me simply &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;ve always
swept.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At last I was lost in the crowd completely, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t make out my bike or the
tree in the distance at all. I looked around me and tapped one of the sweeping
men on the shoulder.  &amp;ldquo;Why do you sweep?&amp;rdquo; I asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a moment he looked at me as if I was strange, then he paused, and a look of
worry came to his face &amp;ndash; it was as if he&amp;rsquo;d not even realized he had been
sweeping all this time! The mere question had snapped him out of a trance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then he was struck by a notion.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adam Smith</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/adam_smith/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/adam_smith/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-stoicism&#34;&gt;On Stoicism&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Human life the Stoics appear to have considered as a game of great skill; in
which, however, there was a mixture of chance [&amp;hellip;] In such games the stake
is commonly a trifle, and the whole pleasure of the game arises from playing
well, from playing fairly, and playing skilfully. If notwithstanding all his
skill, however, the good player should, by the influence of chance, happen to
lose, the loss ought to be a matter, rather of merriment, than of serious
sorrow. He has made no false stroke; he has done nothing which he ought to be
ashamed of; he has enjoyed completely the whole pleasure of the game. [&amp;hellip;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our only anxious concern ought to be, not about the stake, but about the
proper method of playing. If we placed our happiness in winning the stake, we
placed it in what depended upon causes beyond our power, and out of our
direction. We necessarily exposed ourselves to perpetual fear and uneasiness,
and frequently to grievous and mortifying disappointments. If we placed it in
playing well, in playing fairly, in playing wisely and skilfully; in the
propriety of our own conduct in short; we placed it in what, by proper
discipline, education, and attention, might be altogether in our own power,
and under our own direction. Our happiness was perfectly secure, and beyond
the reach of fortune.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Enemy Of Your Enemy</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/enemy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/enemy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the enemy of your enemy is your friend, then by the transitive property, if any of your enemies are enemies, you are your enemy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unless the friend of your enemy is not your enemy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>