<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hannaharendt on Noam&#39;s Website About Software</title>
    <link>http://noamswebsite.com/rtags/hannaharendt/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hannaharendt on Noam&#39;s Website About Software</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://noamswebsite.com/rtags/hannaharendt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Hannah Arendt</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/hannah_arendt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/hannah_arendt/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;understanding&#34;&gt;Understanding&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I am working, I am not interested in how my work might affect people.
[And when I am finished] I am finished. What is important to me is to
understand. For me, writing is a matter of seeking this understanding …
certain things get formulated. […] What is important to me is the process of
thought itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You ask about the effects of my work on others. If I may wax ironical, that is
a masculine question. Men always want to be terribly influential, but I see
that as somewhat external. Do I imagine myself being influential? No. I want
to understand. And if others understand — in the same sense that I have
understood — that gives me a sense of satisfaction, like feeling at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;marginalization&#34;&gt;Marginalization&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m more than ever of the opinion that a decent human existence is possible
today only on the fringes of society, where one then runs the risk of starving
or being stoned to death. In these circumstances, a sense of humor is a great
help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fundamental deprivation of human rights is manifested first and above all
in the deprivation of a place in the world which makes opinions significant
and actions effective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a human being loses political status. [&amp;hellip;] It seems that a man who is
nothing but a man has lost the very qualities which make it possible for other
people to treat him as a fellow-man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is quite conceivable, and even within the realm of practical political
possibilities, that one fine day a highly organized and mechanized humanity
will conclude quite democratically &amp;ndash; namely by majority decision &amp;ndash; that for
humanity as a whole it would be better to liquidate certain parts thereof.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;agency&#34;&gt;Agency&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It just doesn’t look good when a woman gives orders. She should try not to get
herself into such situations if she wants to remain feminine. Whether I am
right about this I do not know. I myself have lived in accordance to this more
or less unconsciously — or let us rather say, more or less consciously. The
problem itself played no role for me personally. To put it very simply, I have
always done what I liked to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often misquoted by critics. Whether Hannah lived in a society that deemed her
worthy or capable of pursuing her interests was irrelevant. This society and its
opinions were a thing that existed beyond the scope of her personal influence.
She neither questioned her worthiness nor waited for permission. She simply
acted. She asserted control of the only social agent over which she had control:
herself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of humanity, when purged of all sentimentality, has the very serious
consequence that in one form or another men must assume responsibility for all
crimes committed by men and that all nations share the onus of evil committed
by all others. Shame at being a human being is the purely individual and still
non-political expression of this insight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>