<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Noam&#39;s Website About Software</title>
    <link>http://noamswebsite.com/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Noam&#39;s Website About Software</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://noamswebsite.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Hannah Arendt</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/hannah_arendt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/hannah_arendt/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;understanding&#34;&gt;Understanding&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I am working, I am not interested in how my work might affect people.
[And when I am finished] I am finished. What is important to me is to
understand. For me, writing is a matter of seeking this understanding …
certain things get formulated. […] What is important to me is the process of
thought itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You ask about the effects of my work on others. If I may wax ironical, that is
a masculine question. Men always want to be terribly influential, but I see
that as somewhat external. Do I imagine myself being influential? No. I want
to understand. And if others understand — in the same sense that I have
understood — that gives me a sense of satisfaction, like feeling at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;marginalization&#34;&gt;Marginalization&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m more than ever of the opinion that a decent human existence is possible
today only on the fringes of society, where one then runs the risk of starving
or being stoned to death. In these circumstances, a sense of humor is a great
help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fundamental deprivation of human rights is manifested first and above all
in the deprivation of a place in the world which makes opinions significant
and actions effective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a human being loses political status. [&amp;hellip;] It seems that a man who is
nothing but a man has lost the very qualities which make it possible for other
people to treat him as a fellow-man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is quite conceivable, and even within the realm of practical political
possibilities, that one fine day a highly organized and mechanized humanity
will conclude quite democratically &amp;ndash; namely by majority decision &amp;ndash; that for
humanity as a whole it would be better to liquidate certain parts thereof.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;agency&#34;&gt;Agency&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It just doesn’t look good when a woman gives orders. She should try not to get
herself into such situations if she wants to remain feminine. Whether I am
right about this I do not know. I myself have lived in accordance to this more
or less unconsciously — or let us rather say, more or less consciously. The
problem itself played no role for me personally. To put it very simply, I have
always done what I liked to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often misquoted by critics. Whether Hannah lived in a society that deemed her
worthy or capable of pursuing her interests was irrelevant. This society and its
opinions were a thing that existed beyond the scope of her personal influence.
She neither questioned her worthiness nor waited for permission. She simply
acted. She asserted control of the only social agent over which she had control:
herself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of humanity, when purged of all sentimentality, has the very serious
consequence that in one form or another men must assume responsibility for all
crimes committed by men and that all nations share the onus of evil committed
by all others. Shame at being a human being is the purely individual and still
non-political expression of this insight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John Stuart Mill</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/john_stuart_mill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/john_stuart_mill/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;on-freedom-of-speech&#34;&gt;On Freedom Of Speech&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have now recognised the necessity to the mental well-being of mankind (on
which all their other well-being depends) of freedom of opinion, and freedom
of the expression of opinion, on four distinct grounds; which we will now
briefly recapitulate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, if any opinion is compelled to silence, that opinion may, for aught we
can certainly know, be true. To deny this is to assume our own infallibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, though the silenced opinion be an error, it may, and very commonly
does, contain a portion of truth; and since the general or prevailing opinion
on any subject is rarely or never the whole truth, it is only by the collision
of adverse opinions that the remainder of the truth has any chance of being
supplied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thirdly, even if the received opinion be not only true, but the whole truth;
unless it is suffered to be, and actually is, vigorously and earnestly
contested, it will, by most of those who receive it, be held in the manner of
a prejudice, with little comprehension or feeling of its rational grounds. And
not only this, but, fourthly, the meaning of the doctrine itself will be in
danger of being lost, or enfeebled, and deprived of its vital effect on the
character and conduct: the dogma becoming a mere formal profession,
inefficacious for good, but cumbering the ground, and preventing the growth of
any real and heartfelt conviction, from reason or personal experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweep</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/sweep/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/sweep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was on my regular afternoon bike ride when I noticed a crowd of people
sweeping the walkways. I leaned my bike on a tree and  went to the first man and
asked &amp;ldquo;Why do you sweep?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I sweep because I resign,&amp;rdquo; he said to me.&amp;ldquo;I used to go blue in the face with
how dirty these streets were. But it was no use, they paid no attention, and I
would go mad each day when upon arriving I would dirty my carpet. I swear I was
losing my mind. I would shout and complain and nobody did a damn thing. Finally
I resigned to the situation. And I was struck by a notion, that only one thing
was within my reach to do, and I got myself this broom and since then I keep my
head down and sweep.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;And what if another walks on your path and muddies it again?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Then I sweep.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thanked the man and went on to the next one and asked &amp;ldquo;Why do you sweep?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I sweep because someone has to. I always suspected these streets were not as
clean as they could be, but none would have it,&amp;rdquo; he answered, then looked both
ways to check if anyone was eavesdropping before adding &amp;ldquo;downright dirty,
actually &amp;ndash; and then one day I saw that man over there sweeping. So I got a
broom and started sweeping too.&amp;rdquo; He paused for a moment, tired, then looked at
me again with pride: &amp;ldquo;Look how clean my walkway is!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving on, I asked another group of people, further down the crowd why they
swept: &amp;ldquo;Well, we sweep because it&amp;rsquo;s proper,&amp;rdquo; answered one. &amp;ldquo;We saw those over
there doing it, and it seemed like a good enough thing to do to join in. The
streets are much cleaner now, don&amp;rsquo;t you see?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked further into the crowd, some were sweeping more vigorously than others,
but even the lazy ones stood with brooms in their hands and talked of how much
they loved to sweep, and again I asked one &amp;ldquo;Why do you sweep?&amp;rdquo; and he said &amp;ldquo;We
sweep because everyone sweeps. How else do you think these streets would stay so
clean?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And a little further down, I asked again and one said to me simply &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;ve always
swept.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At last I was lost in the crowd completely, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t make out my bike or the
tree in the distance at all. I looked around me and tapped one of the sweeping
men on the shoulder.  &amp;ldquo;Why do you sweep?&amp;rdquo; I asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a moment he looked at me as if I was strange, then he paused, and a look of
worry came on his face, and it was as if he&amp;rsquo;d not even realized he had been
sweeping all this time, like the mere question had snapped him out of a trance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then he was struck by a notion.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yutaka Taniyama</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/yutaka_taniyama/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/yutaka_taniyama/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-him&#34;&gt;About Him&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was not a very careful person as a mathematician. He made a lot of
mistakes. But he made mistakes in a good direction. I tried to imitate him.
But I’ve realized that it’s very difficult to make good mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adam Smith</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/adam_smith/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/adam_smith/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-stoicism&#34;&gt;On Stoicism&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Human life the Stoics appear to have considered as a game of great skill; in
which, however, there was a mixture of chance [&amp;hellip;] In such games the stake
is commonly a trifle, and the whole pleasure of the game arises from playing
well, from playing fairly, and playing skilfully. If notwithstanding all his
skill, however, the good player should, by the influence of chance, happen to
lose, the loss ought to be a matter, rather of merriment, than of serious
sorrow. He has made no false stroke; he has done nothing which he ought to be
ashamed of; he has enjoyed completely the whole pleasure of the game. [&amp;hellip;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our only anxious concern ought to be, not about the stake, but about the
proper method of playing. If we placed our happiness in winning the stake, we
placed it in what depended upon causes beyond our power, and out of our
direction. We necessarily exposed ourselves to perpetual fear and uneasiness,
and frequently to grievous and mortifying disappointments. If we placed it in
playing well, in playing fairly, in playing wisely and skilfully; in the
propriety of our own conduct in short; we placed it in what, by proper
discipline, education, and attention, might be altogether in our own power,
and under our own direction. Our happiness was perfectly secure, and beyond
the reach of fortune.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Completely</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/completely/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/completely/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I die, I hope it&amp;rsquo;s completely.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creative</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/creative/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/creative/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Is it courage to, or incapacity not-to?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creative person has the courage to experience opposites of his nature and to attempt some reconciliation of them in an individuated expression of himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.brainpickings.org/2016/12/29/the-creative-architect/&#34;&gt;The Creative Architect&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Enemy Of Your Enemy</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/enemy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/enemy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the enemy of your enemy is your friend, then by the transitive property, if any of your enemies are enemies, you are your enemy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unless the friend of your enemy is not your enemy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elixir/Erlang Resources</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/wiki-main/computers/elixir_resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 16:11:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/wiki-main/computers/elixir_resources/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;learning&#34;&gt;Learning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Title&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://a.co/hjRDstC&#34;&gt;Elixir In Action&lt;/a&gt; (book)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;My go-to recommendation for getting started with Elixir.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@diamondgfx/introduction-fe138ac6079d&#34;&gt;Writing A Blog Engine in Phoenix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Great first tutorial for Phoenix framework&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.erlang-in-anger.com/&#34;&gt;Erlang In Anger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Great guide for when stuff goes bad.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;memory-gc&#34;&gt;Memory / GC&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Title&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hamidreza-s.github.io/erlang/scheduling/real-time/preemptive/migration/2016/02/09/erlang-scheduler-details.html&#34;&gt;Erlang Scheduler Details and Why It Matters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hamidreza-s.github.io/erlang%20garbage%20collection%20memory%20layout%20soft%20realtime/2015/08/24/erlang-garbage-collection-details-and-why-it-matters.html&#34;&gt;Erlang Garbage Collection Details and Why It Matters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Simple introduction to Erlang GC concepts. Start here.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.erlang-solutions.com/blog/erlang-19-0-garbage-collector.html&#34;&gt;Erlang 19.0 Garbage Collector&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://erlang.org/doc/efficiency_guide/introduction.html&#34;&gt;Erlang Efficiency Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.bugsense.com/post/74179424069/erlang-binary-garbage-collection-a-lovehate&#34;&gt;Erlang Binary Garbage Collection: A love/hate relationship&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Some findings on the shared heap GC.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;concurrency&#34;&gt;Concurrency&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Title&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jlouisramblings.blogspot.ca/2013/01/how-erlang-does-scheduling.html?m=1&#34;&gt;How Erlang does scheduling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://kth.diva-portal.org/smash/record.jsf?searchId=2&amp;amp;pid=diva2%3A392243&amp;amp;dswid=-8162&#34;&gt;Characterizing the Scalability of Erlang VM on Many-core Processors&lt;/a&gt; (pdf)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>React Resources</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/wiki-main/computers/react_resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 14:41:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/wiki-main/computers/react_resources/</guid>
      <description>&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Title&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Format&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://teropa.info/blog/2015/09/10/full-stack-redux-tutorial.html&#34;&gt;A Comprehensive Guide to Test-First Development with Redux, React, and Immutable&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;tutorial&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Great comprehensive introduction to the whole ecosystem.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/-jwQ3sGoiXg&#34;&gt;Redux, Re-fram, Relay, Om/next, oh my!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;video&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Resources</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/wiki-main/ml/ml_resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 11:05:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/wiki-main/ml/ml_resources/</guid>
      <description>&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Title&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Format&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;A Tutorial On Deep Learning (&lt;a href=&#34;http://cs.stanford.edu/~quocle/tutorial1.pdf&#34;&gt;Pt 1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://cs.stanford.edu/~quocle/tutorial2.pdf&#34;&gt;Pt 2&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Quoc V. Le (Google)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Separate Ecto From Phoenix In Umbrella App</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/wiki-main/computers/phoenix_no_ecto/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:52:25 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/wiki-main/computers/phoenix_no_ecto/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;First, create umbrella application:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ mix new --umbrella my_app
$ cd my_app/apps
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next create Phoenix app, excluding Ecto:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ mix phoenix.new web --no-ecto
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we create a new mix project for Ecto, with supervision tree:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ mix new db --sup
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally we need to set up some configuration files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;setting-up-db-project&#34;&gt;Setting Up Db Project&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ cd db
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First in the &lt;code&gt;db&lt;/code&gt; project (following the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://hexdocs.pm/ecto/getting-started.html&#34;&gt;getting started&lt;/a&gt; docs for Ecto:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;mix.exs&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (note that we do not need to register &lt;code&gt;:ecto&lt;/code&gt; application)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  def application do
    [applications: [:logger, :postgrex],
     mod: {Db, []}]
  end

  defp deps do
    [{:postgrex, &amp;quot;~&amp;gt; 0.13.0&amp;quot;},
     {:ecto, &amp;quot;~&amp;gt; 2.1.1&amp;quot;}]
  end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Run configuration by running:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ mix ecto.gen.repo -r Db.Repo
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will populate &lt;code&gt;lib/db/repo.ex&lt;/code&gt; and  &lt;code&gt;config.config.exs&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;lib/db.ex&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;children = [
  supervisor(Db.Repo, [])
]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;optional&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We probably want configs for multiple environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;config/config.exs&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uncomment the last line, or replace the contents of the file with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;use Mix.Config

config :db,
  ecto_repos: [Db.Repo]

# Import environment specific config. This must remain at the bottom
# of this file so it overrides the configuration defined above.
import_config &amp;quot;#{Mix.env}.exs&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will load environment-specific configs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;config/dev.exs&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;use Mix.Config

config :db, Db.Repo,
  adapter: Ecto.Adapters.Postgres,
  username: &amp;quot;foo&amp;quot;,
  database: &amp;quot;myproject_dev&amp;quot;,
  hostname: &amp;quot;localhost&amp;quot;,
  pool_size: 10
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;config/test.exs&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;use Mix.Config

config :db, Db.Repo,
  adapter: Ecto.Adapters.Postgres,
  username: &amp;quot;foo&amp;quot;,
  password: &amp;quot;12345&amp;quot;,
  database: &amp;quot;myproject_test&amp;quot;,
  hostname: &amp;quot;localhost&amp;quot;,
  pool: Ecto.Adapters.SQL.Sandbox

config :logger,
  backends: [:console],
  compile_time_purge_level: :debug
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;set-up-phoenix-app&#34;&gt;Set Up Phoenix App&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ cd ../web
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;mix.exs&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  def application do
    [mod: {Web, []},
     applications: [:phoenix_ecto, :db]]
  end

  defp deps do
    [{:phoenix_ecto, &amp;quot;~&amp;gt; 3.2.1&amp;quot;},
     {:db, in_umbrella: true}]
  end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;config/config.exs&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;config :web,
  ecto_repos: [Db.Repo]

# Configure phoenix generators
config :phoenix, :generators,
  migration: false
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;From now on, when running &lt;code&gt;mix phoenix.gen.html&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;mix phoenix.gen.json&lt;/code&gt;,
pass the &lt;code&gt;--no-model&lt;/code&gt; option.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since app is umbrella app now, remember to &lt;code&gt;cd&lt;/code&gt; into phoenix app directory
before running generators, or files will be generated at umbrella&amp;rsquo;s top level.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is it there a way to make it so that there&amp;rsquo;s no need for &lt;code&gt;--no-model&lt;/code&gt; option
every time?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using The Same bashrc / zshrc Across Computers</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/wiki-main/computers/sync_bashrc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:19:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/wiki-main/computers/sync_bashrc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is a simple method I use to share the same &lt;code&gt;.bashrc&lt;/code&gt; / &lt;code&gt;.zshrc&lt;/code&gt; /
&lt;code&gt;.bash_profile&lt;/code&gt; on multiple computers, while still retaining unique
settings where I need them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suppose you want some special setting to apply only to your linux laptop, but
not to your mac laptop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ mkdir ~/configs
$ touch ~/.is_linux
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;if [ -f &#39;.is_linux&#39; ]; then
    echo &amp;quot;This message only shows on my Linux laptops!&amp;quot;
fi
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now with different config files you can configure different environments from
is single universal &lt;code&gt;*rc&lt;/code&gt; file you keep in a
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/noam87/DOTfiles&#34;&gt;dotfiles&lt;/a&gt; repo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it. It&amp;rsquo;s not fancy, but it works.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Dearest Zuckerberg #2</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/w/zuck2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/w/zuck2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My Dearest Zuckerberg,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the elderly grocerystoreman has lost his mind. Why is it that whenever
I visit his store so that I may purchase one of his goods (puddings by the
pound and junk and spiced killgrinded cow in an addictively unsatisfying stale
orange envelope made of, presumably, wheat, or corn? (The kind that when I bite
on it it sticks to my teeth and stains my palate with thoughts of
factory-cookeries somewhere in a third world country)) UP pops he like a wildly
flankhaired coocoobird, sharp hairy ear and nosetendrils protruding at the dent
of his upper lip reminding one of&amp;hellip; of, DEATH! The shadowy claws of DEATH
protruding from and clawing at the face of a man who can no longer hear or
smell yet insists to do and die in slow motion before my very eyes, each day
wrinkling further in imperceptible ways and in UNMENTIONABLE places, gibbering
an ineffectual recombinant pidgin of tongues that tickle barely my ear so that
here and there I say &amp;ldquo;Ah!&amp;rdquo; and smile simply and there and here he SUDDENLY JABS
me with English and I scramble but, Zuck, off he goes again into the structured
madness of a verbal semiotics which my neural net can interpret only as noise,
white and black and peppered like swirlylocks of a middleaged lothario, slave
still and for one last go to that shriveled greedy chromosome, and why not,
buying pounds for pounds, indiscriminately and without remorse, as he surely
was some many married lustless lustra prior, which he must remember fondly
whenever a goodsome pair of gelatinous mounds tingle his doorbell? Where was he
before and what was he doing there and why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish I could understand Cantonese too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Pair Of Dirty Shoes</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/w/shoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/w/shoes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A second pair stacked on top. Dirty socks. Dirty shirts. Piles of them.  That
chair I don&amp;rsquo;t even like. Too many cups. A clean bedroom, the bed made. Clean
dishes, one of those pluggable scented candles. His records. My records. Too
much space.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>