<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Noam&#39;s Website About Software</title>
    <link>http://noamswebsite.com/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Noam&#39;s Website About Software</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://noamswebsite.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Beliefs Vs Conclusions</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/conclusions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/conclusions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;belief&lt;/strong&gt; is axiomatic. It&amp;rsquo;s what one holds to be true. They are at the core
of our interpretation of the world around us, and our understanding of what is
&amp;ldquo;true&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with mathematical axioms, beliefs are by necessity
arbitrary. Whether one asserts with certainty &amp;ldquo;Freedom is desirable&amp;rdquo; or
&amp;ldquo;Subjugation is justified&amp;rdquo; in the end comes down to choosing to believe so (Even
if the first is further derived from the belief that &amp;ldquo;Suffering in others is
bad&amp;rdquo;, that in itself must be arbitrarily asserted, and so on).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;, as the name implies, is some terminal point at the end of a
chain of logical assertions, ultimately stemming from one&amp;rsquo;s beliefs, and
whatever information is available to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it goes without saying: whatever information &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; available to one at all
times is incomplete or incorrect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the same information, but different beliefs, two individuals will arrive
at different conclusions; each conclusion being perfectly logical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose your axioms carefully!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the same beliefs, but different subsets of all of the information about a
subject, two individuals will arrive, again logically, at different conclusions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reconsider your conclusions always. Ask: what would I have concluded had &lt;code&gt;x&lt;/code&gt;
unknown been such and such? Or, what would I have concluded if I were to believe
&lt;code&gt;B&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code&gt;A&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From studying the mathematical foundations of logic we know that, by playing and
combining competing sets of axioms (and even logics themselves), and arriving at
(sometimes contradictory) conclusions, we gain a richer understanding of the
&amp;ldquo;truths&amp;rdquo; that exist within the mathematical spectrum&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As such, one must be careful not to fool oneself into believing one has, or is
capable of arriving at a &amp;ldquo;Truth&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Even if such one exists, can it even be
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/G%C3%B6del&#39;s_incompleteness_theorems&#34;&gt;formulated&lt;/a&gt;?
Can such a formulation be trusted? It&amp;rsquo;s turtles all the way down.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One&amp;rsquo;s beliefs and conclusions, even if &amp;ldquo;logically&amp;rdquo; formulated, at any given
time, even if one can suspend all belief and assume to possess all relevant
information, even then all we can aspire for is that our cherished conclusions
be, at best, one of many equally valid readings of the &amp;ldquo;Truth&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way to go about, if one desires not to go completely mad, is to pick
one, or a few, and be mindful that each one of these is simply one more way of
further enriching our flavor of reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; I think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    At the same time, thinking too much about the philosophical and existential
    implications of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Formalism_(philosophy_of_mathematics)&#34;&gt;mathematical
    formalism&lt;/a&gt;
    is bound to drive one absolutely mad. &lt;em&gt;Caveat emptor&lt;/em&gt;!
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Political Views</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/political_views/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/political_views/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an attempt to succinctly state my political views.
My beliefs will be inherently arbitrary, and my conclusions inevitably based
on incomplete or false knowledge &amp;ndash; however we are all political beings, and
should at the very least be held responsible to understand &lt;em&gt;ourselves&lt;/em&gt; as
such.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I mean by &amp;ldquo;belief&amp;rdquo; is explained &lt;a href=&#34;http://noamswebsite.com/r/conclusions/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I was pressed to categorize myself as a subscriber to some political creed, I
guess I&amp;rsquo;m something like a
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Libertarian_socialism&#34;&gt;libertarian socialist&lt;/a&gt;,
though I certainly part ways here when it comes to their notion that abolishing
the state altogether is somehow desirable (even if it &lt;em&gt;were&lt;/em&gt; a possibility that
exists anywhere outside the pipe-dreams of the anarchist&amp;rsquo;s fancy).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The political theorists who have influenced me most are
&lt;a href=&#34;http://noamswebsite.com/q/john_stuart_mill/&#34;&gt;John Stuart Mill&lt;/a&gt;,
Noam Chomsky, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://noamswebsite.com/q/hannah_arendt/&#34;&gt;Hannah Arendt&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of particular interest to me at the moment is the Rojava experiment, and the
post-incarceration writings of Abdullah Öcalan on his political theory of
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Democratic_Confederalism&#34;&gt;democratic confederalism&lt;/a&gt;.
His short book on the matter is available as a free PDF
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.freeocalan.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/Ocalan-Democratic-Confederalism.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Whether Öcalan and the Rojava experiment will succeed in their putative
goals, and the sincerity of those goals, remains to be seen; but one must admire
the extent to which this vision is being put to practice; and the writings are
both refreshing and real-world applicable.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a socialist in the sense that I believe any defensible political system must
strive to minimize excessive suffering and coercion and provide some level of
comfort given the resources that are available to it as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a staunch individualist in the sense that I believe that ideal political
systems are those that allow the individual to flourish, and to experience life,
by his own terms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From this stems my complete rejection of not only right-wing libertarianism,
but also radical egalitarianism: they are both antithetical to individuality
(one by means of coercion or marginalization, the other by means of
extinguishing individuality altogether!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Here the notion of &amp;ldquo;individual&amp;rdquo; can be extended to groups of individuals,
cultures, and peoples. With this addendum the question naturally arises on the
perils of ascribing &amp;ldquo;personhood&amp;rdquo; to collectives: the privileges of which must
not to dwarf those of the individual person.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Friedrich Nietzsche</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/nietzsche/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/nietzsche/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;anti-semitism&#34;&gt;Anti-Semitism&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(In letter to his sister.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now it has gone so far that I have to defend myself hand and foot against
people who confuse me with these anti-Semitic canaille; after my own sister,
my former sister, and after Widemann more recently have given the impetus to
this most dire of all confusions. After I read the name Zarathustra in the
anti-Semitic Correspondence my forbearance came to an end. I am now in a
position of emergency defense against your spouse&amp;rsquo;s Party. These accursed
anti-Semite deformities shall not sully my ideal!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am just having all anti-Semites shot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;truth&#34;&gt;Truth&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The falseness of an opinion is not for us any objection to it: it is here,
perhaps, that our new language sounds most strangely. The question is, how
far an opinion is life-furthering, life-preserving, species-preserving,
perhaps species-rearing, and we are fundamentally inclined to maintain that
the falsest opinions (to which the synthetic judgments a priori belong), are
the most indispensable to us, that without a recognition of logical fictions,
without a comparison of reality with the purely &lt;em&gt;imagined&lt;/em&gt; world of the
absolute and immutable, without a constant counterfeiting of the world by
means of numbers, man could not live&amp;ndash;that the renunciation of false opinions
would be a renunciation of life, a negation of life. &lt;em&gt;to recognise untruth as
a conditioN of life&lt;/em&gt;; that is certainly to impugn the traditional ideas of
value in a dangerous manner, and a philosophy which ventures to do so, has
thereby alone placed itself beyond good and evil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is certainly not the least charm of a theory that it is refutable; it is
precisely thereby that it attracts the more subtle minds. It seems that the
hundred-times-refuted theory of the &amp;ldquo;free will&amp;rdquo; owes its persistence to this
charm alone; some one is always appearing who feels himself strong enough to
refute it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is it that forces us in general to the supposition that there is an
essential opposition of &amp;ldquo;true&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;false&amp;rdquo;? Is it not enough to suppose
degrees of seemingness, and as it were lighter and darker shades and tones of
semblance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of the French Revolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The text has disappeared under the interpretation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;axioms&#34;&gt;Axioms&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are still harmless self-observers who believe that there are &amp;ldquo;immediate
certainties&amp;rdquo;; for instance, &amp;ldquo;I think,&amp;rdquo; [&amp;hellip;] I would repeat it, however, a
hundred times, that &amp;ldquo;immediate certainty,&amp;rdquo; as well as &amp;ldquo;absolute knowledge&amp;rdquo;
and the &amp;ldquo;thing in itself,&amp;rdquo; involve a &lt;em&gt;contradictio in adjecto&lt;/em&gt;; we really
ought to free ourselves from the misleading significance of words! The people
on their part may think that cognition is knowing all about things, but the
philosopher must say to himself: &amp;ldquo;When I analyze the process that is
expressed in the sentence, &amp;lsquo;I think,&amp;rsquo; I find a whole series of daring
assertions, the argumentative proof of which would be difficult, perhaps
impossible: for instance, that it is &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; who think, that there must
necessarily be something that thinks, that thinking is an activity and
operation on the part of a being who is thought of as a cause, that there is
an &amp;lsquo;ego,&amp;rsquo; and finally, that it is already determined what is to be designated
by thinking &amp;ndash;that I &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; what thinking is. [&amp;hellip;] In short, the assertion
&amp;lsquo;I think,&amp;rsquo; assumes that I &lt;em&gt;compare&lt;/em&gt; my state at the present moment with other
states of myself which I know, in order to determine what it is; on account
of this retrospective connection with further &amp;lsquo;knowledge,&amp;rsquo; it has, at any
rate, no immediate certainty for me.&amp;rdquo; [&amp;hellip;] He who ventures to answer these
metaphysical questions at once by an appeal to a sort of &lt;em&gt;intuitive&lt;/em&gt;
perception, like the person who says, &amp;ldquo;I think, and know that this, at least,
is true, actual, and certain&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; will encounter a smile and two notes of
interrogation in a philosopher nowadays. &amp;ldquo;Sir,&amp;rdquo; the philosopher will perhaps
give him to understand, &amp;ldquo;it is improbable that you are not mistaken, but why
should it be the truth?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gödeless gracious what a conundrum!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;solitude&#34;&gt;Solitude&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am solitude become man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I go into solitude so as not to drink out of everybody&amp;rsquo;s cistern. When I am
among the many I live as the many do, and I do not think I really think.
After a time it always seems as if they want to banish my self from myself
and rob me of my soul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have people around you who are as a garden &amp;ndash; or as music on the waters at
eventide, when already the day becomes a memory. Choose the &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; solitude,
the free, wanton, lightsome solitude, which also gives you the right still to
remain good in any sense whatsoever! How poisonous, how crafty, how bad, does
every long war make one, which cannot be waged openly by means of force! How
&lt;em&gt;personal&lt;/em&gt; does a long fear make one, a long watching of enemies, of possible
enemies!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually one must do everything &lt;em&gt;oneself&lt;/em&gt; in order to know something; which means that one has &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; to do!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;social-impulses&#34;&gt;Social Impulses&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not to speak of the stupidity of moral indignation, which is the unfailing
sign in a philosopher that the sense of philosophical humour has left him.
The martyrdom of the philosopher, his &amp;ldquo;sacrifice for the sake of truth,&amp;rdquo;
forces into the light whatever of the agitator and actor lurks in him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might be possible for a highly developed man, supposing him to degenerate
and go to ruin, to acquire qualities thereby alone, for the sake of which he
would have to be honoured as a saint in the lower world into which he had
sunk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;youth&#34;&gt;Youth&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later on, when the young soul, tortured by continual disillusions, finally
turns suspiciously against itself &amp;ndash; still ardent and savage even in its
suspicion and remorse of conscience: how it upbraids itself, how impatiently
it tears itself, how it revenges itself for its long self-blinding, as though
it had been a voluntary blindness! In this transition one punishes oneself by
distrust of one&amp;rsquo;s sentiments; one tortures one&amp;rsquo;s enthusiasm with doubt, one
feels even the good conscience to be a danger, as if it were the
self-concealment and lassitude of a more refined uprightness; and above all,
one espouses upon principle the cause &lt;em&gt;against&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;youth.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; A decade later,
and one comprehends that all this was also still &amp;ndash; youth!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;revolt&#34;&gt;Revolt&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Enlightenment&amp;rdquo; causes revolt, for the slave desires the unconditioned, he
understands nothing but the tyrannous, even in morals, he loves as he hates,
without &lt;em&gt;nuance&lt;/em&gt;, to the very depths, to the point of pain, to the point of
sickness &amp;ndash; his many &lt;em&gt;hidden&lt;/em&gt; sufferings make him revolt against the noble
taste which seems to &lt;em&gt;deny&lt;/em&gt; suffering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mob Authority</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/mob/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/mob/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a funny contradiction with supposed anti-authoritarians who revel in the
chaos of mobs: what more intractably illegitimate form of authority exists
than that of a mob?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Startup Resources</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/wiki-main/career/startup_resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/wiki-main/career/startup_resources/</guid>
      <description>&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Title&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Format&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/yossorion/4965df74fd6da6cdc280ec57e83a202d&#34;&gt;What I Wish I&amp;rsquo;d Known Before Joining A Unicorn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HTML&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elixir/Erlang Performance Tips</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/wiki-main/computers/elixir_performance_tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/wiki-main/computers/elixir_performance_tips/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t have processes the many other processes depend on. For example, a
single-process cache that many others call to. This will be a bottleneck
because you&amp;rsquo;ll always have to wait for that process&amp;rsquo;s turn from the scheduler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It Sort Of Alliterates</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/w/it_sort_of_alliterates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/w/it_sort_of_alliterates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;pre&gt;
I&#39;m a cheerful ball of clay
See me rolling down the slope
Tumbling forth stochastically
Slowly gathering full shape
My only maker gravity
Molded of some dust and rain
And salt and pressed to solid form
Out of which grass blades cut through
And another and more still
Softening the tumble more
They extend toward the sun
Growing roots that soak and feed
That chip and crack me outside in
Turning clay to dust again
&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources About Compilers</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/wiki-main/computers/compilers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/wiki-main/computers/compilers/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;garbage-collection&#34;&gt;Garbage Collection&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;http://noamswebsite.com/wiki-main/computers/elixir_resources&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for examples with Erlang VM
GC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Title&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/abhinaba/2009/03/02/back-to-basics-generational-garbage-collection/&#34;&gt;Back To Basics: Generational Garbage Collection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blaise Pascal</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/pascal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/pascal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of humanity&amp;rsquo;s problems stem from man&amp;rsquo;s inability to sit quietly in a room
alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epictetus</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/epictetus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/epictetus/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;enchiridion&#34;&gt;Enchiridion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;x&#34;&gt;X&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the occasion of every accident (event) that befalls you, remember to turn
to yourself and inquire what power you have for turning it to use. If you see
a fair man or a fair woman, you will find that the power to resist is
temperance (continence). If labour (pain) be presented to you, you will find
that it is endurance. If it be abusive words, you will find it to be
patience. And if you have been thus formed to the (proper) habit, the
appearances will not carry you along with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;xi&#34;&gt;XI&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never say about any thing, I have lost it, but say I have restored it. Is
your child dead? It has been restored. Is your wife dead? She has been
restored. Has your estate been taken from you? Has not then this also been
restored? But he who has taken it from me is a bad man. But what is it to
you, by whose hands the giver demanded it back? So long as he may allow you,
take care of it as a thing which belongs to another, as travellers do with
their inn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;xvii&#34;&gt;XVII&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember that thou art an actor in a play, of such a kind as the teacher
(author) may choose; if short, of a short one; if long, of a long one: if he
wishes you to act the part of a poor man, see that you act the part
naturally; if the part of a lame man, of a magistrate, of a private person,
(do the same). For this is your duty, to act well the part that is given to
you; but to select the part, belongs to another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;xxi&#34;&gt;XXI&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let death and exile and every other thing which appears dreadful be daily
before your eyes; but most of all death: and you will never think of any
thing mean nor will you desire any thing extravagantly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;xxiii&#34;&gt;XXIII&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a man has reported to you, that a certain person speaks ill of you, do not
make any defence to what has been told you: but reply, The man did
not know the rest of my faults, for he would not have mentioned these only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;xxxv&#34;&gt;XXXV&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you have decided that a thing ought to be done and are doing it, never
avoid being seen doing it, though the many shall form an unfavourable opinion
about it. For if it is not right to do it, avoid doing the thing; but if it
is right, why are you afraid of those who shall find fault wrongly?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;xvii-1&#34;&gt;XVII&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have assumed a character above your strength, you have both acted in
this matter in an unbecoming way, and you have neglected that which you might
have fulfilled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;xliii&#34;&gt;XLIII&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every thing has two handles, the one by which it may be borne, the other by
which it may not. If your brother acts unjustly, do not lay hold of the act
by that handle wherein he acts unjustly, for this is the handle which cannot
be borne: but lay hold of the other, that he is your brother, that he was
nurtured with you, and you will lay hold of the thing by that handle by which
it can be borne.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;xlvi&#34;&gt;XLVI&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On no occasion call yourself a philosopher, and do not speak much among the
uninstructed about theorems (philosophical rules, precepts): but do that
which follows from them. For example at a banquet do not say how a man ought
to eat, but eat as you ought to eat. For remember that in this way Socrates
also altogether avoided ostentation: persons used to come to him and ask to
be recommended by him to philosophers, and he used to take them to
philosophers: so easily did he submit to being overlooked. Accordingly if any
conversation should arise among uninstructed persons about any theorem,
generally be silent; for there is great danger that you will immediately
vomit up what you have not digested. And when a man shall say to you, that
you know nothing, and you are not vexed, then be sure that you have begun the
work (of philosophy). For even sheep do not vomit up their grass and show to
the shepherds how much they have eaten; but when they have internally
digested the pasture, they produce externally wool and milk. Do you also show
not your theorems to the uninstructed, but show the acts which come from
their digestion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;xlviii&#34;&gt;XLVIII&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The condition and characteristic of an uninstructed person is this: he never
expects from himself profit (advantage) nor harm, but from externals. The
condition and characteristic of a philosopher is this: he expects all
advantage and all harm from himself. The signs (marks) of one who is making
progress are these: he censures no man, he praises no man, he blames no man,
he accuses no man, he says nothing about himself as if he were somebody or
knew something; when he is impeded at all or hindered, he blames himself: if
a man praises him, he ridicules the praiser to himself: if a man censures
him, he makes no defence: he goes about like weak persons, being careful not
to move any of the things which are placed, before they are firmly fixed: he
removes all desire from himself, and he transfers aversion
(ἔκκλισιν)&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; to those things only of the things within our power
which are contrary to nature: he employs a moderate movement towards every
thing: whether he is considered foolish or ignorant, he cares not: and in a
word he watches himself as if he were an enemy and lying in ambush.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;pre&gt;
1) Turning of one&amp;rsquo;s course, deflexion.
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geoffrey Chaucer</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/geoffrey_chaucer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/geoffrey_chaucer/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;advice&#34;&gt;Advice&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
Whoso that nil be war by othere men,
By him shal othere men corrected be.
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;He who isn&amp;rsquo;t warned by other men&amp;rsquo;s example, will himself become an example for
other men.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;truth&#34;&gt;Truth&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
Flee fro the prees&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;, and dwelle with sothfastnesse,
Suffyce unto thy good, though hit be smal;
For hord hath hate, and climbing tikelnesse&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;,
Prees hath envye, and wele blent&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; overal;
Savour no more than thee bihove shal;
Werk wel thy-self, that other folk canst rede;
And trouthe shal delivere, hit is no drede.

Tempest thee noght al croked to redresse&lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;,
In trust of hir that turneth as a bal&lt;sup&gt;5&lt;/sup&gt;:
Gret reste stant in litel besinesse;
And eek be war to sporne ageyn an al;
Stryve noght, as doth the crokke with the wal.
Daunte thy-self, that dauntest otheres dede;
And trouthe shal delivere, hit is no drede.

That thee is sent, receyve in buxumnesse,
The wrastling for this worlde axeth a fal.
Her nis non hoom, her nis but wildernesse:
Forth, pilgrim, forth! Forth, beste, out of thy stal!

Know thy contree, look up, thank God of al;
Hold the hye wey, and lat thy gost thee lede:
And trouthe shal delivere, hit is no drede.
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;pre&gt;
1) Crowd (the ambitious crowd at court).
2) Instability.
3) Blinds.
4) Don&amp;rsquo;t trouble yourself trying to straighten everything that&amp;rsquo;s crooked.
5) &amp;ldquo;Trust in her that turns like a ball.&amp;rdquo; (i.e: fortune.)
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;poverty&#34;&gt;Poverty&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
Juvenal seith of poverte myrily:
`The povre man, whan he goth by the weye,
Bifore the theves he may synge and pleye.&#39;
Poverte is hateful good, and, as I gesse,
A ful greet bryngere out of bisynesse;
A greet amender eek of sapience
To hym that taketh it in pacience.
Poverte is this, although it seme alenge,
Possessioun, that no wight wol chalenge.
Poverte ful ofte, whan a man is lowe,
Maketh his God and eek hymself to knowe.
Poverte a spectacle is, as thynketh me,
Thurgh which he may hise verray freendes see.
And therfore, sire, syn that I noght yow greve,
Of my poverte namoore ye me repreve.
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;death&#34;&gt;Death&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
And certeinly, a man hath moost honour
To dyen in his excellence and flour,
Whan he is siker of his goode name,
Thanne hath he doon his freend ne hym no shame.
And gladder oghte his freend been of his deeth,
Whan with honour up yolden in his breeth,
Than whan his name apalled is for age;
For al forgeten is his vassellage.
Thanne is it best as for a worthy fame,
To dyen whan that he is best of name.
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hannah Arendt</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/hannah_arendt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/hannah_arendt/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;understanding&#34;&gt;Understanding&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I am working, I am not interested in how my work might affect people.
[And when I am finished] I am finished. What is important to me is to
understand. For me, writing is a matter of seeking this understanding …
certain things get formulated. […] What is important to me is the process of
thought itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You ask about the effects of my work on others. If I may wax ironical, that is
a masculine question. Men always want to be terribly influential, but I see
that as somewhat external. Do I imagine myself being influential? No. I want
to understand. And if others understand — in the same sense that I have
understood — that gives me a sense of satisfaction, like feeling at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;collective-guilt-and-the-doctrine-of-race&#34;&gt;Collective Guilt And The Doctrine Of Race&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Emphasis mine.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many years now we have met Germans who declare that they are ashamed of
being Germans. I have often felt tempted to answer that I am ashamed of being
human. This elemental shame, which many people of the most various
nationalities share with one another today [&amp;hellip;] has not yet found an
adequate political expression. Our fathers&amp;rsquo; enchantment with humanity was of
a sort which not only light-mindedly ignored the national question; what is
far worse, it did not even conceive of the terror of the idea of humanity and
of the Judeo-Christian faith in the unitary origin of the human race. It was
not very pleasant even when we had to bury our false illusions about &amp;ldquo;the
noble savage,&amp;rdquo; having discovered that men were capable of being cannibals.
Since then peoples have learned to know one another better and learned more
and more about the evil potentialities in men. &lt;strong&gt;The result has been that
they have recoiled more and more from the idea of humanity and become more
susceptible to the doctrine of race, which denies the very possibility of a
common humanity. They instinctively felt that the idea of humanity, whether
it appears in a religious or humanistic form, implies the obligation of a
general responsibility which they do not wish to assume. For the idea of
humanity, when purged ofall sentimentality, has the very serious consequence
that in one form or an­other men must assume responsibility for all crimes
committed by men and that all nations share the onus of evil committed by all
others.&lt;/strong&gt; Shame at being a human being is the purely individual and still
non-political expression of this insight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon them and only upon them, who are filled with a genuine fear of the
inescapable guilt of the human race, can there be any reliance when it comes
to fighting fearlessly, uncompromisingly, everywhere against the incalculable
evil that men are capable of bringing about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;marginalization&#34;&gt;Marginalization&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m more than ever of the opinion that a decent human existence is possible
today only on the fringes of society, where one then runs the risk of starving
or being stoned to death. In these circumstances, a sense of humor is a great
help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fundamental deprivation of human rights is manifested first and above all
in the deprivation of a place in the world which makes opinions significant
and actions effective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[&amp;hellip;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a human being loses political status. [&amp;hellip;] It seems that a man who is
nothing but a man has lost the very qualities which make it possible for other
people to treat him as a fellow-man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is quite conceivable, and even within the realm of practical political
possibilities, that one fine day a highly organized and mechanized humanity
will conclude quite democratically &amp;ndash; namely by majority decision &amp;ndash; that for
humanity as a whole it would be better to liquidate certain parts thereof.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[The Jews] always had to pay with political misery for social glory and with social insult for political success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exceptional Jews knew quite well that it was this very ambiguity &amp;ndash; that they
were Jews and yet presumably not &lt;em&gt;like&lt;/em&gt; Jews &amp;ndash; which opened the doors of
society to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conforming to a society which discriminated against &amp;ldquo;ordinary&amp;rdquo; Jews and in which, at the same time, it was generally easier for an educated Jew to be admitted to fashionable circles than for a non-Jew of similar condition, Jews had to differentiate themselves clearly from the &amp;ldquo;Jew in general&amp;rdquo;, and just as clearly to indicate that they were Jews; under no circumstances were they allowed simply to disappear among their neighbors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;agency&#34;&gt;Agency&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It just doesn’t look good when a woman gives orders. She should try not to get
herself into such situations if she wants to remain feminine. Whether I am
right about this I do not know. I myself have lived in accordance to this more
or less unconsciously — or let us rather say, more or less consciously. The
problem itself played no role for me personally. To put it very simply, I have
always done what I liked to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often misquoted by critics. Whether Hannah lived in a society that deemed her
worthy or capable of pursuing her interests was irrelevant. This society and its
opinions were a thing that existed beyond the scope of her personal influence.
She neither questioned her worthiness nor waited for permission. She simply
acted. She asserted control of the only social agent over which she had control:
herself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;imperialism&#34;&gt;Imperialism&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bourgeoisie [&amp;hellip;] up to then had been the first class in history to
achieve economic pre-eminence without aspiring to political rule. [&amp;hellip;]
Imperialism was born when the ruling class in  capitalist production came up
against national limitation to its economic expansion. The bourgeoisie turned
to politics out of economic necessity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;totalitarian-destruction-of-the-individual&#34;&gt;Totalitarian Destruction Of The Individual&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Total domination, which strives to organize the infinite plurality and
differentiation of human beings as if all of humanity were just one
individual, is possible only if each and every person can be reduced to a
never-changing identity of reactions, so that each of these bundles of
reactions can be exchanged at random for any other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Totalitarianism strives not toward despotic rule over men, but toward a
system in which men are superfluous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first essential step on the road to total domination is to kill the
juridical person in man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;totalitarian-ideology&#34;&gt;Totalitarian Ideology&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the claim [of ideologies] to total validity is taken literally they
become the nuclei of logical systems in which, as in the systems of
paranoiacs, everything follows  comprehensibly and even compulsorily once the
first premise is accepted. [&amp;hellip;] Common sense trained in utilitarian thinking
is helpless against the ideological supersense, since totalitarian regimes
establish a functioning world of no-sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Totalitarianism] feverishly seeks to expand, [&amp;hellip;] neither for expansion&amp;rsquo;s
sake nor for profit, but only for ideological reasons: to make the world
consistent, to prove that its respective supersense has been right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-family-man-as-the-great-criminal-of-the-century&#34;&gt;The Family Man As The Great Criminal Of The Century&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had been so accustomed to admire or gently ridicule the family man&amp;rsquo;s kind concern and earnest concentration on the welfare of his family, his solemn determination to make life easy for his wife and children, that we hardly noticed how the devoted &lt;em&gt;paterfamilias&lt;/em&gt;, worried about nothing so much as his security, was transformed under the pressure of the chaotic economic conditions of our time into an involuntary adventurer, who for all his industry and care could never be certain what the next day would bring. [&amp;hellip;] It became clear that for the sake of his pension, his life insurance, the security of his wife and children, such a man was ready to sacrifice his beliefs, his honor, and his human dignity.  It needed only the Satanic genius of Himmler to discover that after such degradation he was entirely prepared to do anything when the ante was raised and the bare existence of his family was threatened.  The only condition he put was that he should be fully exempted from responsibility for his acts.  Thus that very person, the average German, whom the Nazis notwithstanding years of the most furious propaganda could not induce to kill a Jew on his own account (not even when they made it quite clear that such a murder would go unpunished), now serves the machine of destruction without opposition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The transformation of the family man from a responsible member of society,
interested in all public affairs, to a bourgeois concerned only with his
private existence and knowing no civic virtue, is an international modern
phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He has driven the dichotomy of private and public functions, of family and
occupation, so far that he can no longer find in his own person any
connection between the two. When his occupation forces him to murder people
he does not regard himself as a murderer because he has not done it out of
inclination but in his professional capacity. Out of sheer passion he would
never do harm to a fly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Henri Frédéric Amiel</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/amiel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/amiel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He who floats with the current, who does not guide himself according to
higher principles, who has no ideal, no convictions, &amp;ndash; such a man is a mere
article of the world&amp;rsquo;s furniture &amp;ndash; a thing moved, instead of a living and
moving being &amp;ndash; an echo, not a voice. The man who has no inner life is the
slave of his surroundings, as the barometer is the obedient servant of the
air at rest, and the weathercock the humble servant of the air in motion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>James Baldwin</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/james_baldwin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/james_baldwin/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;spoken-video&#34;&gt;Spoken / Video&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buckley Debate At Cambridge&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/oFeoS41xe7w&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Baldwin&amp;rsquo;s Nigger&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/DeFpzp1pBjc&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Debate With Malcolm X (Audio Only (Can anyone find the full recording? It cuts out at the end.))&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-JIp9_IIV3s&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sentimentality&#34;&gt;Sentimentality&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sentimentality, the ostentatious parading of excessive and spurious emotion,
is the mark of dishonesty, the inability to feel; the wet eyes of the
sentimentalist betray his aversion to experience, his fear of life, his arid
heart; and it is always, therefore, the signal of secret and violent
inhumanity, the mark of cruelty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;inferiority&#34;&gt;Inferiority&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is the peculiar triumph of society &amp;ndash; and its loss &amp;ndash; that it is able to
convince those people of whom it has given inferior status of the reality of
this decree; it has the force and the weapons to translated its dictum into
fact, so that the allegedly inferior are actually made so, in so far as the
societal realities are concerned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There exists among the intolerable degraded, the perverse and powerful desire
to force into the arena of the actual those fantastic crimes of which they
have been accused, achieving their vengeance and their own destruction
through making the nightmare real.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;american-moral-contradictions&#34;&gt;American Moral Contradictions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Americans, unhappily, have the most remarkable ability to alchemize all
bitter truths into an innocuous but piquant confection and to transform their
moral contradictions, or public discussion of such contradictions, into a
proud decoration, such as are given for heroism on the field of battle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;outsider-insider-dichotomy&#34;&gt;Outsider / Insider Dichotomy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Negroes are Americans and their destiny is the country’s destiny. They have
no other experience besides their experience on this continent and it is an
experience which cannot be rejected, which yet remains to be embraced. [&amp;hellip;]
What most significantly fails to be illuminated here is the paradoxical
adjustment which is perpetually made, the Negro being compelled to accept the
fact that this dark and dangerous and unloved stranger is part of himself
forever. [It is] this necessary ability to contain and even, in the most
honorable sense of the word, to exploit the “nigger,” which lends Negro life
its high element of the ironic and which causes the most well-meaning of
their American critics to make such exhilarating errors when attempting to
understand them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;struggle&#34;&gt;Struggle&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not one of the people who believe that oppression imbues a people with wisdom or insight or sweet charity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;jewish-black-relations&#34;&gt;Jewish-Black Relations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a subterranean assumption that the Jew should “know better,” that he
has suffered enough himself to know what suffering means. [&amp;hellip;] The Jew, by
the nature of his own precarious position, has failed to vindicate this
faith. Jews, like Negroes, must use every possible weapon in order to be
accepted, and must try to cover their vulnerability by a frenzied adoption of
the customs of the country; and the nation’s treatment of Negroes is
unquestionably a custom. The Jew has been taught—and, too often, accepts—the
legend of Negro inferiority; and the Negro, on the other hand, has found
nothing in his experience with Jews to counteract the legend of Semitic
greed. Here the American white Gentile has two legends serving him at once:
he has divided these minorities and he rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But just as a society must have a scapegoat, so hatred must have a symbol. Georgia has the Negro and Harlem has the Jew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John Locke</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/john_locke/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/john_locke/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-difference-of-wit-and-judgement&#34;&gt;The Difference Of Wit And Judgement&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Men who have a great deal of wit, and prompt memories, have not always the
clearest judgment or deepest reason. For wit lying most in the assemblage of
ideas, and putting those together with quickness and variety, wherein can be
found any resemblance or congruity, thereby to make up pleasant pictures and
agreeable visions in the fancy; judgment, on the contrary, lies quite on the
other side, in separating carefully, one from another, ideas wherein can be
found the least difference, thereby to avoid being misled by similitude, and
by affinity to take one thing for another. This is a way of proceeding quite
contrary to metaphor and allusion; wherein for the most part lies that
entertainment and pleasantry of wit, which strikes so lively on the fancy,
and therefore is so acceptable to all people, because its beauty appears at
first sight, and there is required no labor of thought to examine what truth
or reason there is in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>