<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Noam&#39;s Website About Software</title>
    <link>http://noamswebsite.com/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Noam&#39;s Website About Software</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://noamswebsite.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Cool Articles / Papers</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/wiki-main/computers/cool_articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/wiki-main/computers/cool_articles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Title&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://viewsourcecode.org/snaptoken/kilo/&#34;&gt;Build Your Own Text Editor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Really great tutorial (and introduction to C programming and terminal programming)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cs.unm.edu/~crowley/papers/sds.pdf&#34;&gt;Data Structures For Text Sequences&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;strong&gt;PDF&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Napoleon Bonaparte</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/napoleon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/napoleon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the enemy is making a false movement we must take good care not to
interrupt him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You must not fight too often with one enemy, or you will teach him all your
art of war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gottfried Leibniz</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/leibniz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/leibniz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a rule is extremely complex, that which conforms to it passes for random.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John Von Neumann</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/von_neumann/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/von_neumann/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we talk mathematics, we may be discussing a secondary language built on
the primary language of the nervous system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If one has really technically penetrated a subject, things that previously
seemed in complete contrast, might be purely mathematical transformations of
each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-lectures-on-self-replicating-automata-1948&#34;&gt;From Lectures On Self-Replicating Automata (1948?)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An automaton cannot be separated from the milieu to which it responds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is therefore quite possible that we are not too far from the limits of
complication which can be achieved in artificial automata without really
fundamental insights into a theory of information, although one should be very
careful with such statements because they can sound awfully ridiculous 5 years
later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact that natural organisms have such a radically different attitude about
errors and behave so differently when an error occurs is probably connected
with some other traits of natural organisms, which are entirely absent from
our automata. The ability of a natural organism to survive in spite of a high
incidence of error (which our artificial automata are incapable of) probably
requires a very high flexibility and ability of the automaton to watch itself
and reorganize itself. And this probably requires a very considerable autonomy
of parts. There is a high autonomy of parts in the human nervous system. This
autonomy of parts of a system has an effect which is observable in the human
nervous system but not in artificial automata. When parts are autonomous and
able to reorganize themselves, when there are several organs each capable of
taking control in an emergency, an antagonistic relation can develop between
the parts so that they are no longer friendly and cooperative. It is quite
likely that all these phenomena are connected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if the axioms are chosen within the common sense area, it is usually very
difficult to achieve an agreement between two people who have done this
independently. For instance, in the literature of formal logics there are
about as many notations as there are authors, and anybody who has used a
notation for a few weeks feels that it&amp;rsquo;s more or less superior to any other.
So, while the choice of notations, of the elements, is enormously important
and absolutely basic for an application of the axiomatic method, this choice
is neither rigorously justifiable nor humanly unambiguously justifiable. All
one can do is to try to submit a system which will stand up under common sense
criteria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is reason to suspect that our predilection for linear codes, which have
a simple, almost temporal sequence, is chiefly a literary habit, corresponding
to our not particularly high level of combinatorial cleverness, and that a
very efficient language would probably depart from linearity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Bug</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/w/a_bug/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/w/a_bug/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(Unfinished Sketch / In Progress)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
It happed one day that through a thick-leaved forest wondered I
And in that dark buzzed what I thought an ordinary fly

...

&#34;If not to pester me, foul creature, why fly thus at night?&#34;
&#34;Let me demonstrate,&#34; I heard, and sure enough: a light!
&#34;An ordinary bug I am, invisible, by day;
So when the sun is hid I wake&#34;, it said, and lit my way;
And before soon the stars and moon we spotted merrily.
&#34;What such relief!&#34; I thought, then said, and thanked him heartily;
Then brighter still my wingèd friend drew geometric shapes:
Shine where you are seen! we sang,
Shine where you are seen!
&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ambition</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/20170305stoned/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/20170305stoned/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Has ambition ever been observed in other animals?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Globalization</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/completely/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/completely/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Globalization is a rich gated community demolishing your neighborhood, then
installing cheap rentals and hiring you as a maid to help you out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jokes</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/jokes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/jokes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Babies cry and giggle at everything and fall in love with everyone.
To Joke is to prod the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marcus Aurelius</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/marcus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/marcus/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Selections from his meditations (Available
&lt;a href=&#34;http://classics.mit.edu/Antoninus/meditations.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for free. One of
my top 10 favorite books. I re-read them every time I disappoint myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ii&#34;&gt;II&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A limit of time is fixed for thee, which if thou dost not use for clearing
away the clouds from thy mind, it will go and thou wilt go, and it will never
return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through not observing what is in the mind of another man has seldom been seen
to be unhappy; but those who do not observe the movement of their own minds
must of necessity be unhappy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;iii&#34;&gt;III&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must make haste then, not only because we are daily nearer to death, but
also because the conception of things and the understanding of them cease
first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not waste the remainder of thy life in thoughts about others, when thou
dost not refer thy thoughts to some object of common utility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A man should use himself to think of those things only about which if one
should suddenly ask, What hast thou now in thy thoughts? With perfect
openness thou mightest, immediately answer, This or That;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Always to look at things so as to see at the same time what kind of universe
this is, and what kind of use everything performs in it, and what value
everything has with reference to the whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;iv&#34;&gt;IV&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let thy principles be brief and fundamental.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Change thy opinion, if there is any one at hand who sets thee right and moves
thee from any opinion. But this change of opinion must proceed only from a
certain persuasion, as of what is just or of common advantage, and the like,
not because it appears pleasant or brings reputation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many grains of frankincense on the same altar: one falls before, another
falls after; but it makes no difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within ten days thou wilt seem a god to those to whom thou art now a beast
and an ape, if thou wilt return to thy principles and the worship of reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How much trouble he avoids who does not look to see what his neighbour says
or does or thinks, but only to what he does himself, that it may be just and
pure; or as Agathon says, look not round at the depraved morals of others,
but run straight along the line without deviating from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do what is necessary, and whatever the reason of the animal which is
naturally social requires, and as it requires. For this brings not only the
tranquility which comes from doing well, but also that which comes from doing
few things.  For the greatest part of what we say and do being unnecessary,
if a man takes this away, he will have more leisure and less uneasiness.
Accordingly on every occasion a man should ask himself, Is this one of the
unnecessary things? Now a man should take away not only unnecessary acts, but
also, unnecessary thoughts, for thus superfluous acts will not follow after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything is only for a day, both that which remembers and that which is
remembered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything that exists is in a manner the seed of that which will be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;v&#34;&gt;V&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Judge every word and deed which are according to nature to be fit for thee;
and be not diverted by the blame which follows from any people nor by their
words, but if a thing is good to be done or said, do not consider it unworthy
of thee.  For those persons have their peculiar leading principle and follow
their peculiar movement; which things do not thou regard, but go straight on,
following thy own nature and the common nature; and the way of both is one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be not disgusted, nor discouraged, nor dissatisfied, if thou dost not succeed
in doing everything according to right principles; but when thou bast failed,
return back again; [&amp;hellip;] and do not return to philosophy as if she were a
master, but act like those who have sore eyes and apply a bit of sponge and
egg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Art thou angry with him whose armpits stink? Art thou angry with him whose
mouth smells foul? What good will this danger do thee? He has such a mouth,
he has such arm-pits: it is necessary that such an emanation must come from
such things- but the man has reason, it will be said, and he is able, if he
takes pain, to discover wherein he offends- I wish thee well of thy
discovery. Well then, and thou hast reason: by thy rational faculty stir up
his rational faculty; show him his error, admonish him. For if he listens,
thou wilt cure him, and there is no need of anger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;vi&#34;&gt;VI&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How cruel it is not to allow men to strive after the things which appear to
them to be suitable to their nature and profitable! And yet in a manner thou
dost not allow them to do this, when thou art vexed because they do wrong.
For they are certainly moved towards things because they suppose them to be
suitable to their nature and profitable to them.- But it is not so.- Teach
them then, and show them without being angry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accustom thyself to attend carefully to what is said by another, and as much
as it is possible, be in the speaker&amp;rsquo;s mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;vii&#34;&gt;VII&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let not future things disturb thee, for thou wilt come to them, if it shall
be necessary, having with thee the same reason which now thou usest for
present things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think not so much of what thou hast not as of what thou hast: but of the
things which thou hast select the best, and then reflect how eagerly they
would have been sought, if thou hadst them not. At the same time however take
care that thou dost not through being so pleased with them accustom thyself
to overvalue them, so as to be disturbed if ever thou shouldst not have them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed in the case of most pains let this remark of Epicurus aid thee, that
pain is neither intolerable nor everlasting, if thou bearest in mind that it
has its limits, and if thou addest nothing to it in imagination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take care not to feel towards the inhuman, as they feel towards men.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;viii&#34;&gt;VIII&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let no man any longer hear thee finding fault with the court life or with thy
own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter into every man&amp;rsquo;s ruling faculty; and also let every other man enter
into thine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Friedrich Nietzsche</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/nietzsche/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/nietzsche/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;anti-semitism&#34;&gt;Anti-Semitism&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(In letter to his sister.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now it has gone so far that I have to defend myself hand and foot against
people who confuse me with these anti-Semitic canaille; after my own sister,
my former sister, and after Widemann more recently have given the impetus to
this most dire of all confusions. After I read the name Zarathustra in the
anti-Semitic Correspondence my forbearance came to an end. I am now in a
position of emergency defense against your spouse&amp;rsquo;s Party. These accursed
anti-Semite deformities shall not sully my ideal!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am just having all anti-Semites shot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;truth&#34;&gt;Truth&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The falseness of an opinion is not for us any objection to it: it is here,
perhaps, that our new language sounds most strangely. The question is, how
far an opinion is life-furthering, life-preserving, species-preserving,
perhaps species-rearing, and we are fundamentally inclined to maintain that
the falsest opinions (to which the synthetic judgments a priori belong), are
the most indispensable to us, that without a recognition of logical fictions,
without a comparison of reality with the purely &lt;em&gt;imagined&lt;/em&gt; world of the
absolute and immutable, without a constant counterfeiting of the world by
means of numbers, man could not live&amp;ndash;that the renunciation of false opinions
would be a renunciation of life, a negation of life. &lt;em&gt;to recognise untruth as
a conditioN of life&lt;/em&gt;; that is certainly to impugn the traditional ideas of
value in a dangerous manner, and a philosophy which ventures to do so, has
thereby alone placed itself beyond good and evil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is certainly not the least charm of a theory that it is refutable; it is
precisely thereby that it attracts the more subtle minds. It seems that the
hundred-times-refuted theory of the &amp;ldquo;free will&amp;rdquo; owes its persistence to this
charm alone; some one is always appearing who feels himself strong enough to
refute it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is it that forces us in general to the supposition that there is an
essential opposition of &amp;ldquo;true&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;false&amp;rdquo;? Is it not enough to suppose
degrees of seemingness, and as it were lighter and darker shades and tones of
semblance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of the French Revolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The text has disappeared under the interpretation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;axioms&#34;&gt;Axioms&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are still harmless self-observers who believe that there are &amp;ldquo;immediate
certainties&amp;rdquo;; for instance, &amp;ldquo;I think,&amp;rdquo; [&amp;hellip;] I would repeat it, however, a
hundred times, that &amp;ldquo;immediate certainty,&amp;rdquo; as well as &amp;ldquo;absolute knowledge&amp;rdquo;
and the &amp;ldquo;thing in itself,&amp;rdquo; involve a &lt;em&gt;contradictio in adjecto&lt;/em&gt;; we really
ought to free ourselves from the misleading significance of words! The people
on their part may think that cognition is knowing all about things, but the
philosopher must say to himself: &amp;ldquo;When I analyze the process that is
expressed in the sentence, &amp;lsquo;I think,&amp;rsquo; I find a whole series of daring
assertions, the argumentative proof of which would be difficult, perhaps
impossible: for instance, that it is &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; who think, that there must
necessarily be something that thinks, that thinking is an activity and
operation on the part of a being who is thought of as a cause, that there is
an &amp;lsquo;ego,&amp;rsquo; and finally, that it is already determined what is to be designated
by thinking &amp;ndash;that I &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; what thinking is. [&amp;hellip;] In short, the assertion
&amp;lsquo;I think,&amp;rsquo; assumes that I &lt;em&gt;compare&lt;/em&gt; my state at the present moment with other
states of myself which I know, in order to determine what it is; on account
of this retrospective connection with further &amp;lsquo;knowledge,&amp;rsquo; it has, at any
rate, no immediate certainty for me.&amp;rdquo; [&amp;hellip;] He who ventures to answer these
metaphysical questions at once by an appeal to a sort of &lt;em&gt;intuitive&lt;/em&gt;
perception, like the person who says, &amp;ldquo;I think, and know that this, at least,
is true, actual, and certain&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; will encounter a smile and two notes of
interrogation in a philosopher nowadays. &amp;ldquo;Sir,&amp;rdquo; the philosopher will perhaps
give him to understand, &amp;ldquo;it is improbable that you are not mistaken, but why
should it be the truth?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gödeless gracious what a conundrum!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;solitude&#34;&gt;Solitude&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am solitude become man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I go into solitude so as not to drink out of everybody&amp;rsquo;s cistern. When I am
among the many I live as the many do, and I do not think I really think.
After a time it always seems as if they want to banish my self from myself
and rob me of my soul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have people around you who are as a garden &amp;ndash; or as music on the waters at
eventide, when already the day becomes a memory. Choose the &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; solitude,
the free, wanton, lightsome solitude, which also gives you the right still to
remain good in any sense whatsoever! How poisonous, how crafty, how bad, does
every long war make one, which cannot be waged openly by means of force! How
&lt;em&gt;personal&lt;/em&gt; does a long fear make one, a long watching of enemies, of possible
enemies!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually one must do everything &lt;em&gt;oneself&lt;/em&gt; in order to know something; which means that one has &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; to do!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;social-impulses&#34;&gt;Social Impulses&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not to speak of the stupidity of moral indignation, which is the unfailing
sign in a philosopher that the sense of philosophical humour has left him.
The martyrdom of the philosopher, his &amp;ldquo;sacrifice for the sake of truth,&amp;rdquo;
forces into the light whatever of the agitator and actor lurks in him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might be possible for a highly developed man, supposing him to degenerate
and go to ruin, to acquire qualities thereby alone, for the sake of which he
would have to be honoured as a saint in the lower world into which he had
sunk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;youth&#34;&gt;Youth&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later on, when the young soul, tortured by continual disillusions, finally
turns suspiciously against itself &amp;ndash; still ardent and savage even in its
suspicion and remorse of conscience: how it upbraids itself, how impatiently
it tears itself, how it revenges itself for its long self-blinding, as though
it had been a voluntary blindness! In this transition one punishes oneself by
distrust of one&amp;rsquo;s sentiments; one tortures one&amp;rsquo;s enthusiasm with doubt, one
feels even the good conscience to be a danger, as if it were the
self-concealment and lassitude of a more refined uprightness; and above all,
one espouses upon principle the cause &lt;em&gt;against&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;youth.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; A decade later,
and one comprehends that all this was also still &amp;ndash; youth!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;revolt&#34;&gt;Revolt&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Enlightenment&amp;rdquo; causes revolt, for the slave desires the unconditioned, he
understands nothing but the tyrannous, even in morals, he loves as he hates,
without &lt;em&gt;nuance&lt;/em&gt;, to the very depths, to the point of pain, to the point of
sickness &amp;ndash; his many &lt;em&gt;hidden&lt;/em&gt; sufferings make him revolt against the noble
taste which seems to &lt;em&gt;deny&lt;/em&gt; suffering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mob Authority</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/mob/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/mob/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a funny contradiction with supposed anti-authoritarians who revel in the
chaos of mobs: what more intractably illegitimate form of authority exists
than that of a mob?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Startup Resources</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/wiki-main/career/startup_resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/wiki-main/career/startup_resources/</guid>
      <description>&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Title&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Format&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/yossorion/4965df74fd6da6cdc280ec57e83a202d&#34;&gt;What I Wish I&amp;rsquo;d Known Before Joining A Unicorn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HTML&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It Sort Of Alliterates</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/w/it_sort_of_alliterates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/w/it_sort_of_alliterates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;pre&gt;
I&#39;m a cheerful ball of clay
See me rolling down the slope
Tumbling forth stochastically
Slowly gathering full shape
My only maker gravity
Molded of some dust and rain
And salt and pressed to solid form
Out of which grass blades cut through
And another and more still
Softening the tumble more
They extend toward the sun
Growing roots that soak and feed
That chip and crack me outside in
Turning clay to dust again
&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources About Compilers</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/wiki-main/computers/compilers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/wiki-main/computers/compilers/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;garbage-collection&#34;&gt;Garbage Collection&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;http://noamswebsite.com/wiki-main/computers/elixir_resources&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for examples with Erlang VM
GC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Title&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/abhinaba/2009/03/02/back-to-basics-generational-garbage-collection/&#34;&gt;Back To Basics: Generational Garbage Collection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blaise Pascal</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/pascal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/pascal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of humanity&amp;rsquo;s problems stem from man&amp;rsquo;s inability to sit quietly in a room
alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>