<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nonviolence on Noam&#39;s Website About Software</title>
    <link>http://noamswebsite.com/rtags/nonviolence/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nonviolence on Noam&#39;s Website About Software</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://noamswebsite.com/rtags/nonviolence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>John Stuart Mill</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/john_stuart_mill/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/john_stuart_mill/</guid>
      <description>THIS IS A POOPOO DRAFT
Excerpts and notes from Mill&amp;rsquo;s On Liberty. Some are in the form of a question-and-answer dialogue to address common misconceptions about free speech.
In part my goal is to help dispel the idea that free speech advocates are all afflicted by a sort of romantic naivete, foolishly holding on to sentimental notions of man&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;natural right&amp;rdquo; to speak, or are blind to the paradoxical threats that arise from &amp;ldquo;providing aggressors with a platform to spread hate&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; sentiments popularized for example in cartoons like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Martin Luther King Jr.</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/mlk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/mlk/</guid>
      <description>On The Effectiveness Of Bad Men  More and more I feel that the people of ill will have used time much more effectively than have the people of good will.
 This observation rings true to this day, and on almost every social domain. It&amp;rsquo;s truly disheartening, the effectiveness with which the far right and neo-liberal centre have managed to run their political operations and unify their base, and with laser-focus dismantle social and environmental safety nets, metastasize state militarism and police impunity, and pervert our democracies in such a way that they seem now practically engineered to benefit the ultra-wealthy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>