<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Random on Noam&#39;s Website About Software</title>
    <link>http://noamswebsite.com/wikis/random/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Random on Noam&#39;s Website About Software</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://noamswebsite.com/wikis/random/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Jokes</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/jokes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/jokes/</guid>
      <description>Babies cry and giggle at everything and fall in love with everyone. To Joke is to prod the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mob Authority</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/mob/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/mob/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a funny contradiction with anti-authoritarians who revel in the chaos of mobs: what more intractably illegitimate form of authority exists than that of a mob?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stuff I REALLY Recommend</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/recommended/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/recommended/</guid>
      <description>Video Talks  Justice: What&amp;rsquo;s the Right Thing To Do?. Provocative Harvard lecture series on Ethics. Robert Sapolsky: The Biology of Human Behavior. Stanford lecture series. Are you in control of your decisions and personality? Maybe not as much as you think. Everything is a Remix. &amp;ldquo;There be nothing new, but that which is Hath been before&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; (Free) documentary on the history of stealing ideas, and how the current reinterpretation of IP / copyright laws stand in the way of innovation, not help it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweep</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/sweep/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/sweep/</guid>
      <description>I was on my regular afternoon bike ride when I noticed a crowd of people sweeping the walkways. I leaned my bike on a tree and went to the first man and asked &amp;ldquo;Why do you sweep?&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;I sweep because I resign,&amp;rdquo; he said to me.&amp;ldquo;I used to go blue in the face with how dirty these streets were. But it was no use, they paid no attention, and I would go mad each day when upon arriving I would dirty my carpet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Completely</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/completely/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/completely/</guid>
      <description>When I die, I hope it&amp;rsquo;s completely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creative</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/creative/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/creative/</guid>
      <description>Is it courage to, or incapacity not-to?
 The creative person has the courage to experience opposites of his nature and to attempt some reconciliation of them in an individuated expression of himself.
&amp;ndash; The Creative Architect
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Enemy Of Your Enemy</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/enemy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/enemy/</guid>
      <description> If the enemy of your enemy is your friend, then by the transitive property, if any of your enemies are enemies, you are your enemy.
 Unless the friend of your enemy is not your enemy.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The World&#39;s Dumbest Hardest Porblem</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/problem/</guid>
      <description>Sumebody submitted to Hacker News this thing where the only rule is &amp;ldquo;You can&amp;rsquo;t use the letter &amp;lsquo;e&amp;rsquo;.&amp;rdquo;
On may writ lik this.  Or
You can simply pick words without it.  Here&amp;rsquo;s an nteresting puzzle:
One can leave out one letter, &amp;ldquo;e&amp;rdquo;, then another, then another&amp;hellip; and measure at what rate does understandability decrease for people (until eventually it&amp;rsquo;s complete gibberish). Also, given a large enough audience, one could try different combinations of letter-removal order and distribute those randomly, and measure the same&amp;hellip; the question being:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/books/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s something about learning from a physical object that makes things &amp;ldquo;click&amp;rdquo; better in my head (it has volume, texture; a particular smell); and I doubt I&amp;rsquo;m an oddity in this respect &amp;ndash; the root of this effect may be biological: For example, when recalling some piece of information, often I can remember where &amp;ndash; within some textbook I read half a decade ago &amp;ndash; the subject is explained. And I do mean, a literal, physical &amp;ldquo;where&amp;rdquo;: a page, (a thing,) which at all times can be found tucked somewhere within a physical stack of bound paper, which I can touch and feel; I might even remember where I was sitting (or standing, or lying), as I held that particular book, open at that page, when I studied the subject, and what it felt like to the touch, and how the lighting in the room fell on the paper; maybe I jotted some note on the margin, maybe I spilled tea on the pages before, giving that &amp;ldquo;where&amp;rdquo; its own unique irregular texture and color &amp;ndash; all of which my brain will forever associate with that information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stones</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/stones/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/stones/</guid>
      <description>I was at the lake last Summer. I picked a mossy old bench to sit, when a group of adolescents gathered to throw stones into the water. For an hour they busied around, making loud gestures and arguing over whose stone made the bigger splash. They would try every angle, and then bicker about which one spattered out the widest, or which one sent the water flying the highest, and how could they agree on what they&amp;rsquo;d seen if in a moment it was gone?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>