<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nietzsche on Noam&#39;s Website About Software</title>
    <link>http://noamswebsite.com/rtags/nietzsche/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nietzsche on Noam&#39;s Website About Software</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://noamswebsite.com/rtags/nietzsche/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Friedrich Nietzsche</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/nietzsche/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/nietzsche/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;anti-semitism&#34;&gt;Anti-Semitism&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(In letter to his sister.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now it has gone so far that I have to defend myself hand and foot against
people who confuse me with these anti-Semitic canaille; after my own sister,
my former sister, and after Widemann more recently have given the impetus to
this most dire of all confusions. After I read the name Zarathustra in the
anti-Semitic Correspondence my forbearance came to an end. I am now in a
position of emergency defense against your spouse&amp;rsquo;s Party. These accursed
anti-Semite deformities shall not sully my ideal!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am just having all anti-Semites shot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;truth&#34;&gt;Truth&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The falseness of an opinion is not for us any objection to it: it is here,
perhaps, that our new language sounds most strangely. The question is, how
far an opinion is life-furthering, life-preserving, species-preserving,
perhaps species-rearing, and we are fundamentally inclined to maintain that
the falsest opinions (to which the synthetic judgments a priori belong), are
the most indispensable to us, that without a recognition of logical fictions,
without a comparison of reality with the purely &lt;em&gt;imagined&lt;/em&gt; world of the
absolute and immutable, without a constant counterfeiting of the world by
means of numbers, man could not live&amp;ndash;that the renunciation of false opinions
would be a renunciation of life, a negation of life. &lt;em&gt;to recognise untruth as
a conditioN of life&lt;/em&gt;; that is certainly to impugn the traditional ideas of
value in a dangerous manner, and a philosophy which ventures to do so, has
thereby alone placed itself beyond good and evil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is certainly not the least charm of a theory that it is refutable; it is
precisely thereby that it attracts the more subtle minds. It seems that the
hundred-times-refuted theory of the &amp;ldquo;free will&amp;rdquo; owes its persistence to this
charm alone; some one is always appearing who feels himself strong enough to
refute it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is it that forces us in general to the supposition that there is an
essential opposition of &amp;ldquo;true&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;false&amp;rdquo;? Is it not enough to suppose
degrees of seemingness, and as it were lighter and darker shades and tones of
semblance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of the French Revolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The text has disappeared under the interpretation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;axioms&#34;&gt;Axioms&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are still harmless self-observers who believe that there are &amp;ldquo;immediate
certainties&amp;rdquo;; for instance, &amp;ldquo;I think,&amp;rdquo; [&amp;hellip;] I would repeat it, however, a
hundred times, that &amp;ldquo;immediate certainty,&amp;rdquo; as well as &amp;ldquo;absolute knowledge&amp;rdquo;
and the &amp;ldquo;thing in itself,&amp;rdquo; involve a &lt;em&gt;contradictio in adjecto&lt;/em&gt;; we really
ought to free ourselves from the misleading significance of words! The people
on their part may think that cognition is knowing all about things, but the
philosopher must say to himself: &amp;ldquo;When I analyze the process that is
expressed in the sentence, &amp;lsquo;I think,&amp;rsquo; I find a whole series of daring
assertions, the argumentative proof of which would be difficult, perhaps
impossible: for instance, that it is &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; who think, that there must
necessarily be something that thinks, that thinking is an activity and
operation on the part of a being who is thought of as a cause, that there is
an &amp;lsquo;ego,&amp;rsquo; and finally, that it is already determined what is to be designated
by thinking &amp;ndash;that I &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; what thinking is. [&amp;hellip;] In short, the assertion
&amp;lsquo;I think,&amp;rsquo; assumes that I &lt;em&gt;compare&lt;/em&gt; my state at the present moment with other
states of myself which I know, in order to determine what it is; on account
of this retrospective connection with further &amp;lsquo;knowledge,&amp;rsquo; it has, at any
rate, no immediate certainty for me.&amp;rdquo; [&amp;hellip;] He who ventures to answer these
metaphysical questions at once by an appeal to a sort of &lt;em&gt;intuitive&lt;/em&gt;
perception, like the person who says, &amp;ldquo;I think, and know that this, at least,
is true, actual, and certain&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; will encounter a smile and two notes of
interrogation in a philosopher nowadays. &amp;ldquo;Sir,&amp;rdquo; the philosopher will perhaps
give him to understand, &amp;ldquo;it is improbable that you are not mistaken, but why
should it be the truth?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gödeless gracious what a conundrum!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;solitude&#34;&gt;Solitude&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am solitude become man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I go into solitude so as not to drink out of everybody&amp;rsquo;s cistern. When I am
among the many I live as the many do, and I do not think I really think.
After a time it always seems as if they want to banish my self from myself
and rob me of my soul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have people around you who are as a garden &amp;ndash; or as music on the waters at
eventide, when already the day becomes a memory. Choose the &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; solitude,
the free, wanton, lightsome solitude, which also gives you the right still to
remain good in any sense whatsoever! How poisonous, how crafty, how bad, does
every long war make one, which cannot be waged openly by means of force! How
&lt;em&gt;personal&lt;/em&gt; does a long fear make one, a long watching of enemies, of possible
enemies!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually one must do everything &lt;em&gt;oneself&lt;/em&gt; in order to know something; which means that one has &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; to do!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;social-impulses&#34;&gt;Social Impulses&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not to speak of the stupidity of moral indignation, which is the unfailing
sign in a philosopher that the sense of philosophical humour has left him.
The martyrdom of the philosopher, his &amp;ldquo;sacrifice for the sake of truth,&amp;rdquo;
forces into the light whatever of the agitator and actor lurks in him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might be possible for a highly developed man, supposing him to degenerate
and go to ruin, to acquire qualities thereby alone, for the sake of which he
would have to be honoured as a saint in the lower world into which he had
sunk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;youth&#34;&gt;Youth&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later on, when the young soul, tortured by continual disillusions, finally
turns suspiciously against itself &amp;ndash; still ardent and savage even in its
suspicion and remorse of conscience: how it upbraids itself, how impatiently
it tears itself, how it revenges itself for its long self-blinding, as though
it had been a voluntary blindness! In this transition one punishes oneself by
distrust of one&amp;rsquo;s sentiments; one tortures one&amp;rsquo;s enthusiasm with doubt, one
feels even the good conscience to be a danger, as if it were the
self-concealment and lassitude of a more refined uprightness; and above all,
one espouses upon principle the cause &lt;em&gt;against&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;youth.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; A decade later,
and one comprehends that all this was also still &amp;ndash; youth!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;revolt&#34;&gt;Revolt&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Enlightenment&amp;rdquo; causes revolt, for the slave desires the unconditioned, he
understands nothing but the tyrannous, even in morals, he loves as he hates,
without &lt;em&gt;nuance&lt;/em&gt;, to the very depths, to the point of pain, to the point of
sickness &amp;ndash; his many &lt;em&gt;hidden&lt;/em&gt; sufferings make him revolt against the noble
taste which seems to &lt;em&gt;deny&lt;/em&gt; suffering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>