<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Liberalism on Noam&#39;s Website About Software</title>
    <link>http://noamswebsite.com/rtags/liberalism/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Liberalism on Noam&#39;s Website About Software</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://noamswebsite.com/rtags/liberalism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>John Stuart Mill</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/john_stuart_mill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/john_stuart_mill/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;on-freedom-of-speech&#34;&gt;On Freedom Of Speech&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have now recognised the necessity to the mental well-being of mankind (on
which all their other well-being depends) of freedom of opinion, and freedom
of the expression of opinion, on four distinct grounds; which we will now
briefly recapitulate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, if any opinion is compelled to silence, that opinion may, for aught we
can certainly know, be true. To deny this is to assume our own infallibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, though the silenced opinion be an error, it may, and very commonly
does, contain a portion of truth; and since the general or prevailing opinion
on any subject is rarely or never the whole truth, it is only by the collision
of adverse opinions that the remainder of the truth has any chance of being
supplied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thirdly, even if the received opinion be not only true, but the whole truth;
unless it is suffered to be, and actually is, vigorously and earnestly
contested, it will, by most of those who receive it, be held in the manner of
a prejudice, with little comprehension or feeling of its rational grounds. And
not only this, but, fourthly, the meaning of the doctrine itself will be in
danger of being lost, or enfeebled, and deprived of its vital effect on the
character and conduct: the dogma becoming a mere formal profession,
inefficacious for good, but cumbering the ground, and preventing the growth of
any real and heartfelt conviction, from reason or personal experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>