<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cs on Noam&#39;s Website About Software</title>
    <link>http://noamswebsite.com/wikis/cs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cs on Noam&#39;s Website About Software</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://noamswebsite.com/wikis/cs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Conway&#39;s Game Of Life In 298 Characters Of Julia</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/wiki-main/conway/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/wiki-main/conway/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I got distracted playing around with Julia and ended up making this little Conway&amp;rsquo;s Game of Life. Would fit into a tweet if not for the pretty-printing / animation loop!.
Works using matrix operations. Parameters by line (uppercase are matrices):
 d = size of board (dxd). S game / map state in 1 and 0 values for on/off. U = shift board up if left-multiplied, right if right-multiplied. D = down, left.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Math/ML Resources</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/wiki-main/ml/ml_resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/wiki-main/ml/ml_resources/</guid>
      <description>Math    Title Format Notes     What Is Mathematics BOOK    Probability Through Problems PDF ; BOOK Best introductory probability book out there. Learn by discovering!   Essential Linear Algebra with Applications: A Problem-Solving Approach BOOK Learn linear algebra through problems.   Principles And Techniques In Combinatorics BOOK ; PDF Beautiful book: simple, clear explanations, no filler, challenging problems   Putnam And Beyond BOOK Lots of challenging math problems from various competitions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Information Theory Overview</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/wiki-main/ml/information_theory_overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/wiki-main/ml/information_theory_overview/</guid>
      <description>Roadmap based on youtube introductory series.
    Compression (efficiency, source coding) Error Correction (reliability, channel coding)     Information Theory (Math) Losless: source coding theorem, Kraft-McMillan inequality     Lossy: rate distortion theorem    Coding Methods (algorithms) Symbol Code: Huffman codes Hamming codes, BCH codes, Turbocodes, Gallager codes    Stream Codes: arithmetic coding     Information How many bits are needed to encode information:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amdahl&#39;s Law</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/wiki-main/computers/amdahls_law/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/wiki-main/computers/amdahls_law/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As multicore computing becomes the norm (even my phone is dual core!), it&amp;rsquo;s important to understand the benefits and also the limitations of concurrency. Amdahl&amp;rsquo;s Law addresses the latter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s imagine a simple program. It prints &amp;ldquo;Hello World&amp;rdquo; 100 times, then quits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first version of the program is written as a single sequential task: it prints one &amp;ldquo;Hello World&amp;rdquo;, then another, then another, 100 times, then quits.  This program takes some unit of time, $t$ to execute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now say we have a dual-core machine at hand. (My phone, perhaps).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cool, now we can spawn &lt;em&gt;two&lt;/em&gt; tasks that print &amp;ldquo;Hello World&amp;rdquo; 50 times each. And, because our magical imaginary computer experiences no overhead, it takes us exactly $\frac{ t }{ 2 }$ units of time to run our second program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we keep adding more and more processors, until we have 100 concurrent threads printing one &amp;ldquo;Hello World&amp;rdquo; each, and our program runs 100 times faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point we stop: &amp;ldquo;Ah, the trend is clear: more processors equals more speed! No point in continuing this experiment.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A naive (wrong) first guess:&lt;/strong&gt; Given $n$ processors executing a program, the maximum boost in speed is $n$. (That is, we can get our program to run $n$ times faster).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cool! This means that, given enough processors, we could make &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; program run almost instantly. Right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://noamswebsite.com/img/more_cores.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&#34;http://forums.pureoverclock.com/amd/21809-rumor-mill-amd-iv-x12-170-12-cores-24mb-cache-6ghz-2.html#post169754&#34;&gt;Pic original source&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course this is not the case! Enough daydreaming. Let&amp;rsquo;s figure out a more  realistic estimate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rice&#39;s Theorem</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/wiki-main/computers/rices_theorem/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/wiki-main/computers/rices_theorem/</guid>
      <description>Rice&amp;rsquo;s theorem can be stated thus:
 Every non-trivial semantic property of a program is undecidable.
 Before we prove the theorem, let&amp;rsquo;s break down that statement:
&amp;ldquo;Semantic Property&amp;rdquo; A ssemantic property is a property of the language, not the machine that is computing it. For example, this is a semantic property of a language:
 All strings in language $L$ are of the form $1^n0^n$.  This is not a semantic property:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>