<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stoicism on Noam&#39;s Website About Software</title>
    <link>http://noamswebsite.com/rtags/stoicism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Stoicism on Noam&#39;s Website About Software</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://noamswebsite.com/rtags/stoicism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Arthur Schopenhauer</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/schopenhauer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/schopenhauer/</guid>
      <description>Health  In general, nine—tenths of our happiness depends upon health alone. With health, everything is a source of pleasure; without it, nothing else, whatever it may be, is enjoyable; even the other personal blessings, &amp;ndash; a great mind, a happy temperament &amp;ndash; are degraded and dwarfed for want of it. [&amp;hellip;] It follows from all this that the greatest of follies is to sacrifice health for any other kind of happiness, whatever it may be, for gain, advancement, learning or fame, let alone, then, for fleeting sensual pleasures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marcus Aurelius</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/marcus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/marcus/</guid>
      <description>Selections from his meditations (Available here for free. One of my top 10 favorite books. I re-read them every time I disappoint myself.
II  A limit of time is fixed for thee, which if thou dost not use for clearing away the clouds from thy mind, it will go and thou wilt go, and it will never return.
  Through not observing what is in the mind of another man, a man has seldom been seen to be unhappy; but those who do not observe the movement of their own minds must of necessity be unhappy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epictetus</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/epictetus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/epictetus/</guid>
      <description>Enchiridion X  On the occasion of every accident (event) that befalls you, remember to turn to yourself and inquire what power you have for turning it to use. If you see a fair man or a fair woman, you will find that the power to resist is temperance (continence). If labour (pain) be presented to you, you will find that it is endurance. If it be abusive words, you will find it to be patience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adam Smith</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/adam_smith/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/adam_smith/</guid>
      <description>On Stoicism  Human life the Stoics appear to have considered as a game of great skill; in which, however, there was a mixture of chance [&amp;hellip;] In such games the stake is commonly a trifle, and the whole pleasure of the game arises from playing well, from playing fairly, and playing skilfully. If notwithstanding all his skill, however, the good player should, by the influence of chance, happen to lose, the loss ought to be a matter, rather of merriment, than of serious sorrow.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>