<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quotes on Noam&#39;s Website About Software</title>
    <link>http://noamswebsite.com/wikis/quotes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Quotes on Noam&#39;s Website About Software</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://noamswebsite.com/wikis/quotes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Plato</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/plato/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/plato/</guid>
      <description>The people have always some champion whom they set over them and nurse into greatness. This and no other is the root from which a tyrant springs; when he first appears he is a protector.
When the tyrant has disposed of foreign enemies by conquest or treaty, and there is nothing to fear from them, then he is always stirring up some war or other, in order that the people may require a leader.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John Stuart Mill</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/john_stuart_mill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/john_stuart_mill/</guid>
      <description>On Liberty in its entirety is available here for free here: https://www.gutenberg.org/files/34901/34901-h/34901-h.htm
Main Reasons For Protecting Free Speech JS Mill presents the reader with four principal arguments. It should be of note that he does not appeal to man&amp;rsquo;s natural right to free expression, or romantic notions of &amp;ldquo;Truth&amp;rdquo;: Mill is solely concerned about the far-reaching societal consequences of impeding dissent. The four arguments are as follows:
 First, if any opinion is compelled to silence, that opinion may, for aught we can certainly know, be true.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Martin Luther King Jr.</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/mlk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/mlk/</guid>
      <description>On The Effectiveness Of Bad Men  More and more I feel that the people of ill will have used time much more effectively than have the people of good will.
 The Purpose Of Nonviolent Direct Action  I must confess that I am not afraid of the word &amp;ldquo;tension.&amp;rdquo; I have earnestly opposed violent tension, but there is a type of constructive, nonviolent tension which is necessary for growth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arthur Schopenhauer</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/schopenhauer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/schopenhauer/</guid>
      <description>Health  In general, nine—tenths of our happiness depends upon health alone. With health, everything is a source of pleasure; without it, nothing else, whatever it may be, is enjoyable; even the other personal blessings, &amp;ndash; a great mind, a happy temperament &amp;ndash; are degraded and dwarfed for want of it. [&amp;hellip;] It follows from all this that the greatest of follies is to sacrifice health for any other kind of happiness, whatever it may be, for gain, advancement, learning or fame, let alone, then, for fleeting sensual pleasures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/random/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/random/</guid>
      <description> If there&amp;rsquo;s one lawyer in town, they drive a Chevrolet. If there are two lawyers in town, they both drive Cadillacs.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Napoleon Bonaparte</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/napoleon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/napoleon/</guid>
      <description> When the enemy is making a false movement we must take good care not to interrupt him.
  You must not fight too often with one enemy, or you will teach him all your art of war.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gottfried Leibniz</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/leibniz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/leibniz/</guid>
      <description> When a rule is extremely complex, that which conforms to it passes for random.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John Von Neumann</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/von_neumann/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/von_neumann/</guid>
      <description>When we talk mathematics, we may be discussing a secondary language built on the primary language of the nervous system.
  If one has really technically penetrated a subject, things that previously seemed in complete contrast, might be purely mathematical transformations of each other.
 From Lectures On Self-Replicating Automata (1948?)  An automaton cannot be separated from the milieu to which it responds.
  It is therefore quite possible that we are not too far from the limits of complication which can be achieved in artificial automata without really fundamental insights into a theory of information, although one should be very careful with such statements because they can sound awfully ridiculous 5 years later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marcus Aurelius</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/marcus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/marcus/</guid>
      <description>Selections from his meditations (Available here for free. One of my top 10 favorite books. I re-read them every time I disappoint myself.
II  A limit of time is fixed for thee, which if thou dost not use for clearing away the clouds from thy mind, it will go and thou wilt go, and it will never return.
  Through not observing what is in the mind of another man, a man has seldom been seen to be unhappy; but those who do not observe the movement of their own minds must of necessity be unhappy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Friedrich Nietzsche</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/nietzsche/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/nietzsche/</guid>
      <description>Anti-Semitism (In letter to his sister.)
 Now it has gone so far that I have to defend myself hand and foot against people who confuse me with these anti-Semitic canaille; after my own sister, my former sister, and after Widemann more recently have given the impetus to this most dire of all confusions. After I read the name Zarathustra in the anti-Semitic Correspondence my forbearance came to an end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blaise Pascal</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/pascal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/pascal/</guid>
      <description> All of humanity&amp;rsquo;s problems stem from man&amp;rsquo;s inability to sit quietly in a room alone.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epictetus</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/epictetus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/epictetus/</guid>
      <description>Enchiridion X  On the occasion of every accident (event) that befalls you, remember to turn to yourself and inquire what power you have for turning it to use. If you see a fair man or a fair woman, you will find that the power to resist is temperance (continence). If labour (pain) be presented to you, you will find that it is endurance. If it be abusive words, you will find it to be patience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geoffrey Chaucer</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/geoffrey_chaucer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/geoffrey_chaucer/</guid>
      <description>Advice   Whoso that nil be war by othere men, By him shal othere men corrected be.   &amp;ldquo;He who isn&amp;rsquo;t warned by other men&amp;rsquo;s example, will himself become an example for other men.&amp;rdquo;
Truth   Flee fro the prees1, and dwelle with sothfastnesse, Suffyce unto thy good, though hit be smal; For hord hath hate, and climbing tikelnesse2, Prees hath envye, and wele blent3 overal; Savour no more than thee bihove shal; Werk wel thy-self, that other folk canst rede; And trouthe shal delivere, hit is no drede.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hannah Arendt</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/hannah_arendt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/hannah_arendt/</guid>
      <description>Understanding  When I am working, I am not interested in how my work might affect people. [And when I am finished] I am finished. What is important to me is to understand. For me, writing is a matter of seeking this understanding … certain things get formulated. […] What is important to me is the process of thought itself.
  You ask about the effects of my work on others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Henri Frédéric Amiel</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/amiel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/amiel/</guid>
      <description>He who floats with the current, who does not guide himself according to higher principles, who has no ideal, no convictions, &amp;ndash; such a man is a mere article of the world&amp;rsquo;s furniture &amp;ndash; a thing moved, instead of a living and moving being &amp;ndash; an echo, not a voice. The man who has no inner life is the slave of his surroundings, as the barometer is the obedient servant of the air at rest, and the weathercock the humble servant of the air in motion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>James Baldwin</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/james_baldwin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/james_baldwin/</guid>
      <description>Spoken / Video Buckley Debate At Cambridge
 &amp;ldquo;Baldwin&amp;rsquo;s Nigger&amp;rdquo;
 Debate With Malcolm X (Audio Only (Can anyone find the full recording? It cuts out at the end.))
 Sentimentality  Sentimentality, the ostentatious parading of excessive and spurious emotion, is the mark of dishonesty, the inability to feel; the wet eyes of the sentimentalist betray his aversion to experience, his fear of life, his arid heart; and it is always, therefore, the signal of secret and violent inhumanity, the mark of cruelty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John Locke</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/john_locke/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/john_locke/</guid>
      <description>The Difference Of Wit And Judgement  Men who have a great deal of wit, and prompt memories, have not always the clearest judgment or deepest reason. For wit lying most in the assemblage of ideas, and putting those together with quickness and variety, wherein can be found any resemblance or congruity, thereby to make up pleasant pictures and agreeable visions in the fancy; judgment, on the contrary, lies quite on the other side, in separating carefully, one from another, ideas wherein can be found the least difference, thereby to avoid being misled by similitude, and by affinity to take one thing for another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Old Norse Sayings (Vikings)</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/vikings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/vikings/</guid>
      <description> From Hávamál  Praise no day until evening, no wife before cremation, no sword till tested, no maid before marriage, no ice till crossed, no ale till it&amp;rsquo;s drunk.
  Only a fool lies awake all night and broods over his problems. When morning comes he is exhausted. And his troubles are the same as before.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yutaka Taniyama</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/yutaka_taniyama/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/yutaka_taniyama/</guid>
      <description> About Him  He was not a very careful person as a mathematician. He made a lot of mistakes. But he made mistakes in a good direction. I tried to imitate him. But I’ve realized that it’s very difficult to make good mistakes.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adam Smith</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/adam_smith/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/adam_smith/</guid>
      <description>On Stoicism  Human life the Stoics appear to have considered as a game of great skill; in which, however, there was a mixture of chance [&amp;hellip;] In such games the stake is commonly a trifle, and the whole pleasure of the game arises from playing well, from playing fairly, and playing skilfully. If notwithstanding all his skill, however, the good player should, by the influence of chance, happen to lose, the loss ought to be a matter, rather of merriment, than of serious sorrow.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>