<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Individuality on Noam&#39;s Website About Software</title>
    <link>http://noamswebsite.com/rtags/individuality/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Individuality on Noam&#39;s Website About Software</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://noamswebsite.com/rtags/individuality/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>My Political Views</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/political_views/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/political_views/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an attempt to succinctly state my political views.
My beliefs will be inherently arbitrary, and my conclusions inevitably based
on incomplete or false knowledge &amp;ndash; however we are all political beings, and
should at the very least be held responsible to understand &lt;em&gt;ourselves&lt;/em&gt; as
such.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I mean by &amp;ldquo;belief&amp;rdquo; is explained &lt;a href=&#34;http://noamswebsite.com/r/conclusions/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I was pressed to categorize myself as a subscriber to some political creed, I
guess I&amp;rsquo;m something like a
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Libertarian_socialism&#34;&gt;libertarian socialist&lt;/a&gt;,
though I certainly part ways here when it comes to their notion that abolishing
the state altogether is somehow desirable (even if it &lt;em&gt;were&lt;/em&gt; a possibility that
exists anywhere outside the pipe-dreams of the anarchist&amp;rsquo;s fancy).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The political theorists who have influenced me most are
&lt;a href=&#34;http://noamswebsite.com/q/john_stuart_mill/&#34;&gt;John Stuart Mill&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Noam_Chomsky&#34;&gt;Noam Chomsky&lt;/a&gt;, and
&lt;a href=&#34;http://noamswebsite.com/q/hannah_arendt/&#34;&gt;Hannah Arendt&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of particular interest to me at the moment is the Rojava experiment, and the
post-incarceration writings of Abdullah Öcalan on his political theory of
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Democratic_Confederalism&#34;&gt;democratic confederalism&lt;/a&gt;.
His short book on the matter is available as a free PDF
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.freeocalan.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/Ocalan-Democratic-Confederalism.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Whether Öcalan and the Rojava experiment will succeed in their putative
goals, and the sincerity of those goals, remains to be seen; but one must admire
the extent to which this vision is being put to practice; and the writings are
both refreshing and real-world applicable.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a socialist in the sense that I believe any defensible political system must
strive to minimize excessive suffering and coercion and provide some level of
comfort given the resources that are available to it as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a staunch individualist in the sense that I believe that ideal political
systems are those that allow the individual to flourish, and to experience life,
by his own terms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From this stems my complete rejection of not only right-wing libertarianism,
but also radical egalitarianism: they are both antithetical to individuality
(one by means of coercion or marginalization, the other by means of
extinguishing individuality altogether!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Here the notion of &amp;ldquo;individual&amp;rdquo; can be extended to groups of individuals,
cultures, and peoples. With this addendum the question naturally arises on the
perils of ascribing &amp;ldquo;personhood&amp;rdquo; to collectives: the privileges of which must
not to dwarf those of the individual person.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mob Authority</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/mob/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/mob/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a funny contradiction with supposed anti-authoritarians who revel in the
chaos of mobs: what more intractably illegitimate form of authority exists
than that of a mob?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>