<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on Noam&#39;s Website About Software</title>
    <link>http://noamswebsite.com/wikis/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing on Noam&#39;s Website About Software</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://noamswebsite.com/wikis/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Bug</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/w/a_bug/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/w/a_bug/</guid>
      <description>(Unfinished Sketch / In Progress)
 It happed one day that through a thick-leaved forest wondered I And in that dark buzzed what I thought an ordinary fly ... &#34;If not to pester me, foul creature, why fly thus at night?&#34; &#34;Let me demonstrate,&#34; I heard, and sure enough: a light! &#34;An ordinary bug I am, invisible, by day; So when the sun is hid I wake&#34;, it said, and lit my way; And before soon the stars and moon we spotted merrily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It Sort Of Alliterates</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/w/it_sort_of_alliterates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/w/it_sort_of_alliterates/</guid>
      <description> I&#39;m a cheerful ball of clay See me rolling down the slope Tumbling forth stochastically Slowly gathering full shape My only maker gravity Molded of some dust and rain And salt and pressed to solid form Out of which grass blades cut through And another and more still Softening the tumble more They extend toward the sun Growing roots that soak and feed That chip and crack me outside in Turning clay to dust again  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweep</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/sweep/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/sweep/</guid>
      <description>I was on my regular afternoon bike ride when I noticed a crowd of people sweeping the walkways. I leaned my bike on a tree and went to the first man and asked &amp;ldquo;Why do you sweep?&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;I sweep because I resign,&amp;rdquo; he said to me.&amp;ldquo;I used to go blue in the face with how dirty these streets were. But it was no use, they paid no attention, and I would go mad each day when upon arriving I would dirty my carpet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Dearest Zuckerberg #2</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/w/zuck2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/w/zuck2/</guid>
      <description>My Dearest Zuckerberg,
I think the elderly grocerystoreman has lost his mind. Why is it that whenever I visit his store so that I may purchase one of his goods (puddings by the pound and junk and spiced killgrinded cow in an addictively unsatisfying stale orange envelope made of, presumably, wheat, or corn? (The kind that when I bite on it it sticks to my teeth and stains my palate with thoughts of factory-cookeries somewhere in a third world country)) UP pops he like a wildly flankhaired coocoobird, sharp hairy ear and nosetendrils protruding at the dent of his upper lip reminding one of&amp;hellip; of, DEATH!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Pair Of Dirty Shoes</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/w/shoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/w/shoes/</guid>
      <description>A second pair stacked on top. Dirty socks. Dirty shirts. Piles of them. That chair I don&amp;rsquo;t even like. Too many cups. A clean bedroom, the bed made. Clean dishes, one of those pluggable scented candles. His records. My records. Too much space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stones</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/stones/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/stones/</guid>
      <description>I was at the lake last Summer. I picked a mossy old bench to sit, when a group of adolescents gathered to throw stones into the water. For an hour they busied around, making loud gestures and arguing over whose stone made the bigger splash. They would try every angle, and then bicker about which one spattered out the widest, or which one sent the water flying the highest, and how could they agree on what they&amp;rsquo;d seen if in a moment it was gone?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Girl On A Train Asks About The Book In My Bag</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/w/traingirl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/w/traingirl/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s that book you&amp;rsquo;re reading?&amp;rdquo; she asks.
&amp;ldquo;Ernest Wattle: the story of a man who falls in love with the statue of an ancient goddess.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Sounds strange.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Depends how you read it. It&amp;rsquo;s also the story of Almendra, an ancient goddess who creates a man just so he would love her. But then, through prayer, he brings her statue to life, but she falls in love with someone else.&amp;rdquo;
A quaint-looking pig farm, like something out of a picture book, whizzes across the window.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Little Room</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/w/little_room/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/w/little_room/</guid>
      <description>A set of boots halt just behind Little Room door, mark a pensive hollow in the casted light on Little Room floor, peak an inch or two, bringing with them an ounce of sunshine more, and Little Room croaks.
The door shuts behind them; the sun is silenced again.
Little Room is home to feathered insects; bonsai orchards spring out of cracks on the floor, on which they perch and feed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bursts</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/w/bursts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/w/bursts/</guid>
      <description>The first time he fell in love it was with a girl who always smelled like fresh laundry, and her name was Anna and it was love at first sight, or not quite so, because it wasn&amp;rsquo;t really all at once that he fell in love with her, but in little bursts rather, like the steps up a ladder, or grains of sand piling up at the bottom end of an hourglass, the first of which was him falling madly in love with her back, which was all he could see from where he sat, and all he wanted to see, entranced as he was at that moment by its smooth shape and tender flesh and by the contours of her spine and ribs, which traced sensuous grooves along the pink fabric of her tanktop whenever she took a deep breath, or spoke, or hunched over slightly in order to write something in her notebook, at which point long locks of black hair&amp;ndash;black like tree branches after a forest fire&amp;ndash;would fall and unravel, revealing for him, like curtains being fluttered by a morning breeze, which let slip a first ray of light into the room and wake the dreamer within from his slumber&amp;ndash; yes, exactly like that, they would fall and unravel and reveal to him her neck, her perfect neck, he thought, which was the next thing he fell in love with, followed by her dainty hands, and then the freckles on her face, which she hated, which he loved, adored, and, this is true, that very same winter he even fell in love with a certain bubbly noise her nose was making because she was trying to be as quiet as possible when sniffling every so often because she had had a cold and a runny nose, so he offered her a tissue, but really it was just so he could lean close enough to smell her, and to look into her eyes, which, he thought, gazing, small and dark and rounded, were like an infinitely dark abyss that gazed also into him, which he knew, of course, because the only reason he had read that damn book was because he had seen it poking out of her bag that one time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Wouldn&#39;t Mind Floating Downstream</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/w/downstream/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/w/downstream/</guid>
      <description>&#34;I would not mind floating downstream; End up among the fish and whales. Of the ocean waters, dark and deep, I&#39;m not afraid, for I do know That, once you&#39;ve lived among the corals, The muddy currents, pebbles and rocks, And parlous contours of the stream Against whose tide you&#39;d rather swim Are banes you&#39;ll gladly leave behind; For deep at sea you&#39;re not confined By rocks and edges that grind and rasp-- The river&#39;s water may be sweet, But just as sweet, the river&#39;s shallow; I&#39;d rather down its torrent follow, Follow to the salted sea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Bird By The Window</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/w/bird/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/w/bird/</guid>
      <description>acu riousblue li ttlewing i sawta pingon mywindow like asif onstrings sheelin gered glo wingsof tlyin thesun sowith myfin geri tappedtoo what afun andglad somejoy theli ttleblue birdsang asong tobuoy myheart andbring mecheer not thenlong shestar tedflying there andhere andca lingmee pla yingcir clesin thesky andsaid sheedlike toplay withme: oh penup andcome outside! oh penup and chaseme! idlike tojoin itlooks likefun but alas ican notopen: oh penup youwill enjoyit! and thebreeze isso inviting!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Characters</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/w/characters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/w/characters/</guid>
      <description>They tear up the room, they jest and joke around, and I&amp;rsquo;m that much closer to not being here anymore; but when you have no friends, everyone is your friend. They gist and jitter, like little bugs, they bump into me, sit by my side, lean on me, kiss me, and just as quickly they leave; when I hold one it feels fuzzy, like an idea. &amp;ldquo;Will you ever let me go?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roomly I Dejected Your Enter</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/w/roomly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/w/roomly/</guid>
      <description>Roomly I dejected your enter. We bedded on your sit; Did you kiss to want me? I wanted to bad you kissly, sure. I loved you to make want to too. Real buttly, I felt near you just to get lucky. And your lovely open looked so wide, sweet eyes. Your sweet strawberry tastes like a juicy mouth. O, I&#39;m so long for you, I how in pain! And I want to proclaim my love for my pride, but you swallow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Words</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/w/words/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/w/words/</guid>
      <description> Words don&#39;t listen Words don&#39;t talk Don&#39;t do nothing You write them down They just kind of sit there  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>