<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cognitive on Noam&#39;s Website About Software</title>
    <link>http://noamswebsite.com/rtags/cognitive/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cognitive on Noam&#39;s Website About Software</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://noamswebsite.com/rtags/cognitive/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Beliefs Vs Conclusions</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/conclusions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/conclusions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;belief&lt;/strong&gt; is axiomatic. It&amp;rsquo;s what one holds to be true. They are at the core
of our interpretation of the world around us, and our understanding of what is
&amp;ldquo;true&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with mathematical axioms, beliefs are by necessity
arbitrary. Whether one asserts with certainty &amp;ldquo;Freedom is desirable&amp;rdquo; or
&amp;ldquo;Subjugation is justified&amp;rdquo; in the end comes down to choosing to believe so (Even
if the first is further derived from the belief that &amp;ldquo;Suffering in others is
bad&amp;rdquo;, that in itself must be arbitrarily asserted, and so on).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;, as the name implies, is some terminal point at the end of a
chain of logical assertions, ultimately stemming from one&amp;rsquo;s beliefs, and
whatever information is available to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it goes without saying: whatever information &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; available to one at all
times is incomplete or incorrect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the same information, but different beliefs, two individuals will arrive
at different conclusions; each conclusion being perfectly logical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose your axioms carefully!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the same beliefs, but different subsets of all of the information about a
subject, two individuals will arrive, again logically, at different conclusions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reconsider your conclusions always. Ask: what would I have concluded had &lt;code&gt;x&lt;/code&gt;
unknown been such and such? Or, what would I have concluded if I were to believe
&lt;code&gt;B&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code&gt;A&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From studying the mathematical foundations of logic we know that, by playing and
combining competing sets of axioms (and even logics themselves), and arriving at
(sometimes contradictory) conclusions, we gain a richer understanding of the
&amp;ldquo;truths&amp;rdquo; that exist within the mathematical spectrum&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As such, one must be careful not to fool oneself into believing one has, or is
capable of arriving at a &amp;ldquo;Truth&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Even if such one exists, can it even be
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/G%C3%B6del&#39;s_incompleteness_theorems&#34;&gt;formulated&lt;/a&gt;?
Can such a formulation be trusted? It&amp;rsquo;s turtles all the way down.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One&amp;rsquo;s beliefs and conclusions, even if &amp;ldquo;logically&amp;rdquo; formulated, at any given
time, even if one can suspend all belief and assume to possess all relevant
information, even then all we can aspire for is that our cherished conclusions
be, at best, one of many equally valid readings of the &amp;ldquo;Truth&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way to go about, if one desires not to go completely mad, is to pick
one, or a few, and be mindful that each one of these is simply one more way of
further enriching our flavor of reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; I think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    At the same time, thinking too much about the philosophical and existential
    implications of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Formalism_(philosophy_of_mathematics)&#34;&gt;mathematical
    formalism&lt;/a&gt;
    is bound to drive one absolutely mad. &lt;em&gt;Caveat emptor&lt;/em&gt;!
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Friedrich Nietzsche</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/nietzsche/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/nietzsche/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;anti-semitism&#34;&gt;Anti-Semitism&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(In letter to his sister.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now it has gone so far that I have to defend myself hand and foot against
people who confuse me with these anti-Semitic canaille; after my own sister,
my former sister, and after Widemann more recently have given the impetus to
this most dire of all confusions. After I read the name Zarathustra in the
anti-Semitic Correspondence my forbearance came to an end. I am now in a
position of emergency defense against your spouse&amp;rsquo;s Party. These accursed
anti-Semite deformities shall not sully my ideal!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am just having all anti-Semites shot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;truth&#34;&gt;Truth&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The falseness of an opinion is not for us any objection to it: it is here,
perhaps, that our new language sounds most strangely. The question is, how
far an opinion is life-furthering, life-preserving, species-preserving,
perhaps species-rearing, and we are fundamentally inclined to maintain that
the falsest opinions (to which the synthetic judgments a priori belong), are
the most indispensable to us, that without a recognition of logical fictions,
without a comparison of reality with the purely &lt;em&gt;imagined&lt;/em&gt; world of the
absolute and immutable, without a constant counterfeiting of the world by
means of numbers, man could not live&amp;ndash;that the renunciation of false opinions
would be a renunciation of life, a negation of life. &lt;em&gt;to recognise untruth as
a conditioN of life&lt;/em&gt;; that is certainly to impugn the traditional ideas of
value in a dangerous manner, and a philosophy which ventures to do so, has
thereby alone placed itself beyond good and evil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is certainly not the least charm of a theory that it is refutable; it is
precisely thereby that it attracts the more subtle minds. It seems that the
hundred-times-refuted theory of the &amp;ldquo;free will&amp;rdquo; owes its persistence to this
charm alone; some one is always appearing who feels himself strong enough to
refute it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is it that forces us in general to the supposition that there is an
essential opposition of &amp;ldquo;true&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;false&amp;rdquo;? Is it not enough to suppose
degrees of seemingness, and as it were lighter and darker shades and tones of
semblance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of the French Revolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The text has disappeared under the interpretation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;axioms&#34;&gt;Axioms&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are still harmless self-observers who believe that there are &amp;ldquo;immediate
certainties&amp;rdquo;; for instance, &amp;ldquo;I think,&amp;rdquo; [&amp;hellip;] I would repeat it, however, a
hundred times, that &amp;ldquo;immediate certainty,&amp;rdquo; as well as &amp;ldquo;absolute knowledge&amp;rdquo;
and the &amp;ldquo;thing in itself,&amp;rdquo; involve a &lt;em&gt;contradictio in adjecto&lt;/em&gt;; we really
ought to free ourselves from the misleading significance of words! The people
on their part may think that cognition is knowing all about things, but the
philosopher must say to himself: &amp;ldquo;When I analyze the process that is
expressed in the sentence, &amp;lsquo;I think,&amp;rsquo; I find a whole series of daring
assertions, the argumentative proof of which would be difficult, perhaps
impossible: for instance, that it is &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; who think, that there must
necessarily be something that thinks, that thinking is an activity and
operation on the part of a being who is thought of as a cause, that there is
an &amp;lsquo;ego,&amp;rsquo; and finally, that it is already determined what is to be designated
by thinking &amp;ndash;that I &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; what thinking is. [&amp;hellip;] In short, the assertion
&amp;lsquo;I think,&amp;rsquo; assumes that I &lt;em&gt;compare&lt;/em&gt; my state at the present moment with other
states of myself which I know, in order to determine what it is; on account
of this retrospective connection with further &amp;lsquo;knowledge,&amp;rsquo; it has, at any
rate, no immediate certainty for me.&amp;rdquo; [&amp;hellip;] He who ventures to answer these
metaphysical questions at once by an appeal to a sort of &lt;em&gt;intuitive&lt;/em&gt;
perception, like the person who says, &amp;ldquo;I think, and know that this, at least,
is true, actual, and certain&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; will encounter a smile and two notes of
interrogation in a philosopher nowadays. &amp;ldquo;Sir,&amp;rdquo; the philosopher will perhaps
give him to understand, &amp;ldquo;it is improbable that you are not mistaken, but why
should it be the truth?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gödeless gracious what a conundrum!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;solitude&#34;&gt;Solitude&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am solitude become man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I go into solitude so as not to drink out of everybody&amp;rsquo;s cistern. When I am
among the many I live as the many do, and I do not think I really think.
After a time it always seems as if they want to banish my self from myself
and rob me of my soul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have people around you who are as a garden &amp;ndash; or as music on the waters at
eventide, when already the day becomes a memory. Choose the &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; solitude,
the free, wanton, lightsome solitude, which also gives you the right still to
remain good in any sense whatsoever! How poisonous, how crafty, how bad, does
every long war make one, which cannot be waged openly by means of force! How
&lt;em&gt;personal&lt;/em&gt; does a long fear make one, a long watching of enemies, of possible
enemies!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually one must do everything &lt;em&gt;oneself&lt;/em&gt; in order to know something; which means that one has &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; to do!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;social-impulses&#34;&gt;Social Impulses&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not to speak of the stupidity of moral indignation, which is the unfailing
sign in a philosopher that the sense of philosophical humour has left him.
The martyrdom of the philosopher, his &amp;ldquo;sacrifice for the sake of truth,&amp;rdquo;
forces into the light whatever of the agitator and actor lurks in him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might be possible for a highly developed man, supposing him to degenerate
and go to ruin, to acquire qualities thereby alone, for the sake of which he
would have to be honoured as a saint in the lower world into which he had
sunk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;youth&#34;&gt;Youth&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later on, when the young soul, tortured by continual disillusions, finally
turns suspiciously against itself &amp;ndash; still ardent and savage even in its
suspicion and remorse of conscience: how it upbraids itself, how impatiently
it tears itself, how it revenges itself for its long self-blinding, as though
it had been a voluntary blindness! In this transition one punishes oneself by
distrust of one&amp;rsquo;s sentiments; one tortures one&amp;rsquo;s enthusiasm with doubt, one
feels even the good conscience to be a danger, as if it were the
self-concealment and lassitude of a more refined uprightness; and above all,
one espouses upon principle the cause &lt;em&gt;against&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;youth.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; A decade later,
and one comprehends that all this was also still &amp;ndash; youth!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;revolt&#34;&gt;Revolt&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Enlightenment&amp;rdquo; causes revolt, for the slave desires the unconditioned, he
understands nothing but the tyrannous, even in morals, he loves as he hates,
without &lt;em&gt;nuance&lt;/em&gt;, to the very depths, to the point of pain, to the point of
sickness &amp;ndash; his many &lt;em&gt;hidden&lt;/em&gt; sufferings make him revolt against the noble
taste which seems to &lt;em&gt;deny&lt;/em&gt; suffering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blaise Pascal</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/pascal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/pascal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of humanity&amp;rsquo;s problems stem from man&amp;rsquo;s inability to sit quietly in a room
alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epictetus</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/epictetus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/epictetus/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;enchiridion&#34;&gt;Enchiridion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;x&#34;&gt;X&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the occasion of every accident (event) that befalls you, remember to turn
to yourself and inquire what power you have for turning it to use. If you see
a fair man or a fair woman, you will find that the power to resist is
temperance (continence). If labour (pain) be presented to you, you will find
that it is endurance. If it be abusive words, you will find it to be
patience. And if you have been thus formed to the (proper) habit, the
appearances will not carry you along with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;xi&#34;&gt;XI&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never say about any thing, I have lost it, but say I have restored it. Is
your child dead? It has been restored. Is your wife dead? She has been
restored. Has your estate been taken from you? Has not then this also been
restored? But he who has taken it from me is a bad man. But what is it to
you, by whose hands the giver demanded it back? So long as he may allow you,
take care of it as a thing which belongs to another, as travellers do with
their inn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;xvii&#34;&gt;XVII&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember that thou art an actor in a play, of such a kind as the teacher
(author) may choose; if short, of a short one; if long, of a long one: if he
wishes you to act the part of a poor man, see that you act the part
naturally; if the part of a lame man, of a magistrate, of a private person,
(do the same). For this is your duty, to act well the part that is given to
you; but to select the part, belongs to another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;xxi&#34;&gt;XXI&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let death and exile and every other thing which appears dreadful be daily
before your eyes; but most of all death: and you will never think of any
thing mean nor will you desire any thing extravagantly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;xxiii&#34;&gt;XXIII&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a man has reported to you, that a certain person speaks ill of you, do not
make any defence to what has been told you: but reply, The man did
not know the rest of my faults, for he would not have mentioned these only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;xxxv&#34;&gt;XXXV&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you have decided that a thing ought to be done and are doing it, never
avoid being seen doing it, though the many shall form an unfavourable opinion
about it. For if it is not right to do it, avoid doing the thing; but if it
is right, why are you afraid of those who shall find fault wrongly?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;xvii-1&#34;&gt;XVII&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have assumed a character above your strength, you have both acted in
this matter in an unbecoming way, and you have neglected that which you might
have fulfilled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;xliii&#34;&gt;XLIII&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every thing has two handles, the one by which it may be borne, the other by
which it may not. If your brother acts unjustly, do not lay hold of the act
by that handle wherein he acts unjustly, for this is the handle which cannot
be borne: but lay hold of the other, that he is your brother, that he was
nurtured with you, and you will lay hold of the thing by that handle by which
it can be borne.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;xlvi&#34;&gt;XLVI&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On no occasion call yourself a philosopher, and do not speak much among the
uninstructed about theorems (philosophical rules, precepts): but do that
which follows from them. For example at a banquet do not say how a man ought
to eat, but eat as you ought to eat. For remember that in this way Socrates
also altogether avoided ostentation: persons used to come to him and ask to
be recommended by him to philosophers, and he used to take them to
philosophers: so easily did he submit to being overlooked. Accordingly if any
conversation should arise among uninstructed persons about any theorem,
generally be silent; for there is great danger that you will immediately
vomit up what you have not digested. And when a man shall say to you, that
you know nothing, and you are not vexed, then be sure that you have begun the
work (of philosophy). For even sheep do not vomit up their grass and show to
the shepherds how much they have eaten; but when they have internally
digested the pasture, they produce externally wool and milk. Do you also show
not your theorems to the uninstructed, but show the acts which come from
their digestion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;xlviii&#34;&gt;XLVIII&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The condition and characteristic of an uninstructed person is this: he never
expects from himself profit (advantage) nor harm, but from externals. The
condition and characteristic of a philosopher is this: he expects all
advantage and all harm from himself. The signs (marks) of one who is making
progress are these: he censures no man, he praises no man, he blames no man,
he accuses no man, he says nothing about himself as if he were somebody or
knew something; when he is impeded at all or hindered, he blames himself: if
a man praises him, he ridicules the praiser to himself: if a man censures
him, he makes no defence: he goes about like weak persons, being careful not
to move any of the things which are placed, before they are firmly fixed: he
removes all desire from himself, and he transfers aversion
(ἔκκλισιν)&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; to those things only of the things within our power
which are contrary to nature: he employs a moderate movement towards every
thing: whether he is considered foolish or ignorant, he cares not: and in a
word he watches himself as if he were an enemy and lying in ambush.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;pre&gt;
1) Turning of one&amp;rsquo;s course, deflexion.
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Henri Frédéric Amiel</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/amiel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/amiel/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He who floats with the current, who does not guide himself according to
higher principles, who has no ideal, no convictions, &amp;ndash; such a man is a mere
article of the world&amp;rsquo;s furniture &amp;ndash; a thing moved, instead of a living and
moving being &amp;ndash; an echo, not a voice. The man who has no inner life is the
slave of his surroundings, as the barometer is the obedient servant of the
air at rest, and the weathercock the humble servant of the air in motion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>John Locke</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/john_locke/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/john_locke/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-difference-of-wit-and-judgement&#34;&gt;The Difference Of Wit And Judgement&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Men who have a great deal of wit, and prompt memories, have not always the
clearest judgment or deepest reason. For wit lying most in the assemblage of
ideas, and putting those together with quickness and variety, wherein can be
found any resemblance or congruity, thereby to make up pleasant pictures and
agreeable visions in the fancy; judgment, on the contrary, lies quite on the
other side, in separating carefully, one from another, ideas wherein can be
found the least difference, thereby to avoid being misled by similitude, and
by affinity to take one thing for another. This is a way of proceeding quite
contrary to metaphor and allusion; wherein for the most part lies that
entertainment and pleasantry of wit, which strikes so lively on the fancy,
and therefore is so acceptable to all people, because its beauty appears at
first sight, and there is required no labor of thought to examine what truth
or reason there is in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stuff I REALLY Recommend</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/recommended/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/recommended/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;video-talks&#34;&gt;Video Talks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/kBdfcR-8hEY&#34;&gt;Justice: What&amp;rsquo;s the Right Thing To Do?&lt;/a&gt;. Provocative Harvard lecture series on Ethics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/NNnIGh9g6fA&#34;&gt;Robert Sapolsky: The Biology of Human Behavior&lt;/a&gt;. Stanford lecture series. Are you in control of your decisions and personality? Maybe not as much as you think.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/GPYzY9I78CI&#34;&gt;John Ioannidis: &amp;ldquo;Reproducible Research: True or False?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;. Unsettling results: 70%-80% of scientific studies, even from cited, reputable sources, are wrong. On the dangers of ignoring reproducibility in science.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://everythingisaremix.info/&#34;&gt;Everything is a Remix&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;ldquo;There be nothing new, but that which is Hath been before&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; (Free) documentary on the history of stealing ideas, and how the current reinterpretation of IP / copyright laws stand in the way of innovation, not help it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Century Of The Self.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Story Of Maths (4 part series).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/7qUKiHZbVwc&#34;&gt;The Human Animal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Untold History Of The United Stated (series on Netflix).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;books&#34;&gt;Books&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.com/0262510871&#34;&gt;SICP&lt;/a&gt; (or anything else Sussman).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.com/0393913007&#34;&gt;Norton Anthology of English Literature&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://a.co/c1zNqGm&#34;&gt;Principles and Techniques in Combinatorics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://a.co/6VMIaQg&#34;&gt;What Is Mathematics?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.com/0387257659&#34;&gt;Putnam and Beyond&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.com/0815344325&#34;&gt;Molecular Biology of the Cell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meditations of Marcus Aurelius.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Golden Sayings of Epictetus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://a.co/fT21Dzu&#34;&gt;On Crimes And Punishment&lt;/a&gt;, Beccaria (Young translation).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On Liberty, John Stuart Mill.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.com/0942299795&#34;&gt;Society Of The Spectacle&lt;/a&gt; (Nicholson translation).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.com/0578012812&#34;&gt;Getting Real&lt;/a&gt;, Jason Fried&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alice in Wonderland / Through the Looking Glass, Lewis Carroll&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://a.co/2UH8Udf&#34;&gt;The Trial&lt;/a&gt;, Franz Kafka&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://a.co/genNFo1&#34;&gt;Don Quijote De La Mancha&lt;/a&gt;, Miguel de Cervantes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The writings of Hannah Arendt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.com/9505156944&#34;&gt;Mafalda&lt;/a&gt; + Other works of Quino.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yutaka Taniyama</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/yutaka_taniyama/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/yutaka_taniyama/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-him&#34;&gt;About Him&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was not a very careful person as a mathematician. He made a lot of
mistakes. But he made mistakes in a good direction. I tried to imitate him.
But I’ve realized that it’s very difficult to make good mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adam Smith</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/adam_smith/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/adam_smith/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-stoicism&#34;&gt;On Stoicism&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Human life the Stoics appear to have considered as a game of great skill; in
which, however, there was a mixture of chance [&amp;hellip;] In such games the stake
is commonly a trifle, and the whole pleasure of the game arises from playing
well, from playing fairly, and playing skilfully. If notwithstanding all his
skill, however, the good player should, by the influence of chance, happen to
lose, the loss ought to be a matter, rather of merriment, than of serious
sorrow. He has made no false stroke; he has done nothing which he ought to be
ashamed of; he has enjoyed completely the whole pleasure of the game. [&amp;hellip;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our only anxious concern ought to be, not about the stake, but about the
proper method of playing. If we placed our happiness in winning the stake, we
placed it in what depended upon causes beyond our power, and out of our
direction. We necessarily exposed ourselves to perpetual fear and uneasiness,
and frequently to grievous and mortifying disappointments. If we placed it in
playing well, in playing fairly, in playing wisely and skilfully; in the
propriety of our own conduct in short; we placed it in what, by proper
discipline, education, and attention, might be altogether in our own power,
and under our own direction. Our happiness was perfectly secure, and beyond
the reach of fortune.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creative</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/creative/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/creative/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Is it courage to, or incapacity not-to?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creative person has the courage to experience opposites of his nature and to attempt some reconciliation of them in an individuated expression of himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.brainpickings.org/2016/12/29/the-creative-architect/&#34;&gt;The Creative Architect&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stones</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/stones/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/stones/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was at the lake last Summer. I picked a mossy old bench to sit, when a group
of adolescents gathered to throw stones into the water.  For an hour they busied
around, making loud gestures and arguing over whose stone made the bigger
splash.  They would try every angle, and then bicker about which one spattered
out the widest, or which one sent the water flying the highest, and how could
they agree on what they&amp;rsquo;d seen if in a moment it was gone? Finally they
approached me hoping I would settle their dispute, but I&amp;rsquo;d not seen the water
splash&amp;ndash; they scoffed, frustrated, and went on their way, and I was free to
continue watching the ripples that now adorned the surface of the lake.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>