<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cognitive on Noam&#39;s Website About Software</title>
    <link>http://noamswebsite.com/rtags/cognitive/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cognitive on Noam&#39;s Website About Software</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://noamswebsite.com/rtags/cognitive/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Yutaka Taniyama</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/yutaka_taniyama/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/yutaka_taniyama/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-him&#34;&gt;About Him&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was not a very careful person as a mathematician. He made a lot of
mistakes. But he made mistakes in a good direction. I tried to imitate him.
But I’ve realized that it’s very difficult to make good mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adam Smith</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/q/adam_smith/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/q/adam_smith/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-stoicism&#34;&gt;On Stoicism&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Human life the Stoics appear to have considered as a game of great skill; in
which, however, there was a mixture of chance [&amp;hellip;] In such games the stake
is commonly a trifle, and the whole pleasure of the game arises from playing
well, from playing fairly, and playing skilfully. If notwithstanding all his
skill, however, the good player should, by the influence of chance, happen to
lose, the loss ought to be a matter, rather of merriment, than of serious
sorrow. He has made no false stroke; he has done nothing which he ought to be
ashamed of; he has enjoyed completely the whole pleasure of the game. [&amp;hellip;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our only anxious concern ought to be, not about the stake, but about the
proper method of playing. If we placed our happiness in winning the stake, we
placed it in what depended upon causes beyond our power, and out of our
direction. We necessarily exposed ourselves to perpetual fear and uneasiness,
and frequently to grievous and mortifying disappointments. If we placed it in
playing well, in playing fairly, in playing wisely and skilfully; in the
propriety of our own conduct in short; we placed it in what, by proper
discipline, education, and attention, might be altogether in our own power,
and under our own direction. Our happiness was perfectly secure, and beyond
the reach of fortune.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creative</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/creative/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/creative/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Is it courage to, or incapacity not-to?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creative person has the courage to experience opposites of his nature and to attempt some reconciliation of them in an individuated expression of himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.brainpickings.org/2016/12/29/the-creative-architect/&#34;&gt;The Creative Architect&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stones</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/stones/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/stones/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was at the lake last Summer. I picked a mossy old bench to sit, when a group
of adolescents gathered to throw stones into the water.  For an hour they busied
around, making loud gestures and arguing over whose stone made the bigger
splash.  They would try every angle, and then bicker about which one spattered
out the widest, or which one sent the water flying the highest, and how could
they agree on what they&amp;rsquo;d seen if in a moment it was gone? Finally they
approached me hoping I would settle their dispute, but I&amp;rsquo;d not seen the water
splash&amp;ndash; they scoffed, frustrated, and went on their way, and I was free to
continue watching the ripples that now adorned the surface of the lake.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>