<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rs on Noam&#39;s Website About Software</title>
    <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rs on Noam&#39;s Website About Software</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://noamswebsite.com/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Stuff I REALLY Recommend</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/recommended/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/recommended/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-talks&#34;&gt;Video Talks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/kBdfcR-8hEY&#34;&gt;Justice: What&amp;rsquo;s the Right Thing To Do?&lt;/a&gt;. Provocative Harvard lecture series on Ethics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/NNnIGh9g6fA&#34;&gt;Robert Sapolsky: The Biology of Human Behavior&lt;/a&gt;. Stanford lecture series. Are you in control of your decisions and personality? Maybe not as much as you think.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://everythingisaremix.info/&#34;&gt;Everything is a Remix&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;ldquo;There be nothing new, but that which is Hath been before&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; (Free) documentary on the history of stealing ideas, and how the current reinterpretation of IP / copyright laws stand in the way of innovation, not help it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Century Of The Self.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Story Of Maths (4 part series).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/7qUKiHZbVwc&#34;&gt;The Human Animal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Untold History Of The United Stated (series on Netflix).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;books&#34;&gt;Books&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.com/0262510871&#34;&gt;SICP&lt;/a&gt; (or anything else Sussman).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.com/0393913007&#34;&gt;Norton Anthology of English Literature&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://a.co/c1zNqGm&#34;&gt;Principles and Techniques in Combinatorics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://a.co/6VMIaQg&#34;&gt;What Is Mathematics?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.com/0387257659&#34;&gt;Putnam and Beyond&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.com/0815344325&#34;&gt;Molecular Biology of the Cell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meditations of Marcus Aurelius.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Golden Sayings of Epictetus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://a.co/fT21Dzu&#34;&gt;On Crimes And Punishment&lt;/a&gt;, Beccaria (Young translation).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On Liberty, John Stuart Mill.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.com/0942299795&#34;&gt;Society Of The Spectacle&lt;/a&gt; (Nicholson translation).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.com/0578012812&#34;&gt;Getting Real&lt;/a&gt;, Jason Fried&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alice in Wonderland / Through the Looking Glass, Lewis Carroll&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://a.co/2UH8Udf&#34;&gt;The Trial&lt;/a&gt;, Franz Kafka&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://a.co/genNFo1&#34;&gt;Don Quijote De La Mancha&lt;/a&gt;, Miguel de Cervantes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The writings of Hannah Arendt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.com/9505156944&#34;&gt;Mafalda&lt;/a&gt; + Other works of Quino.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweep</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/sweep/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/sweep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was on my regular afternoon bike ride when I noticed a crowd of people
sweeping the walkways. I leaned my bike on a tree and  went to the first man and
asked &amp;ldquo;Why do you sweep?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I sweep because I resign,&amp;rdquo; he said to me.&amp;ldquo;I used to go blue in the face with
how dirty these streets were. But it was no use, they paid no attention, and I
would go mad each day when upon arriving I would dirty my carpet. I swear I was
losing my mind. I would shout and complain and nobody did a damn thing. Finally
I resigned to the situation. And I was struck by a notion, that only one thing
was within my reach to do, and I got myself this broom and since then I keep my
head down and sweep.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;And what if another walks on your path and muddies it again?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Then I sweep.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thanked the man and went on to the next one and asked &amp;ldquo;Why do you sweep?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I sweep because someone has to. I always suspected these streets were not as
clean as they could be, but none would have it,&amp;rdquo; he answered, then looked both
ways to check if anyone was eavesdropping before adding &amp;ldquo;downright dirty,
actually &amp;ndash; and then one day I saw that man over there sweeping. So I got a
broom and started sweeping too.&amp;rdquo; He paused for a moment, tired, then looked at
me again with pride: &amp;ldquo;Look how clean my walkway is!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving on, I asked another group of people, further down the crowd why they
swept: &amp;ldquo;Well, we sweep because it&amp;rsquo;s proper,&amp;rdquo; answered one. &amp;ldquo;We saw those over
there doing it, and it seemed like a good enough thing to do to join in. The
streets are much cleaner now, don&amp;rsquo;t you see?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked further into the crowd, some were sweeping more vigorously than others,
but even the lazy ones stood with brooms in their hands and talked of how much
they loved to sweep, and again I asked one &amp;ldquo;Why do you sweep?&amp;rdquo; and he said &amp;ldquo;We
sweep because everyone sweeps. How else do you think these streets would stay so
clean?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And a little further down, I asked again and one said to me simply &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;ve always
swept.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At last I was lost in the crowd completely, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t make out my bike or the
tree in the distance at all. I looked around me and tapped one of the sweeping
men on the shoulder.  &amp;ldquo;Why do you sweep?&amp;rdquo; I asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a moment he looked at me as if I was strange, then he paused, and a look of
worry came to his face &amp;ndash; it was as if he&amp;rsquo;d not even realized he had been
sweeping all this time! The mere question had snapped him out of a trance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then he was struck by a notion.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Completely</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/completely/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/completely/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I die, I hope it&amp;rsquo;s completely.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creative</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/creative/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/creative/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Is it courage to, or incapacity not-to?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creative person has the courage to experience opposites of his nature and to attempt some reconciliation of them in an individuated expression of himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.brainpickings.org/2016/12/29/the-creative-architect/&#34;&gt;The Creative Architect&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Representative Democracies Are An Inevitable Optimum</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/representative/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/representative/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The existence of power hierarchies is inevitable because of the existence of the
will to power. This is not a moral statement, but an empirical one. However hard
a collective may work at toppling power structures, and even if it is successful
in doing so, new power hierarchies
&lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; emerge, because there will &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; be individuals who will seek to place
themselves at the top.
The only way to escape this would be to eliminate the desire
or means of domination in those who possess them&amp;hellip; but here we reach an
intractable contradiction: because to do so would require the exertion of power
by one group on another (that is, those who seek to topple power must dominate
those who seek that power, and further they would have to collude to retain the
power to do so indefinitely&amp;hellip;  but this dynamic is itself hierarchical!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The optimal solution is therefore to side with a preferred hierarchy. This is
after all what a representative democracy is: to select one&amp;rsquo;s masters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note however that for this strategy to succeed, those at the bottom of the
hierarchy, if they are smart, must at all times mind a singular goal: &lt;strong&gt;To ensure
that their masters do not cooperate beyond a threshold,&lt;/strong&gt;
and to ensure that they exist in a
fragmented state, so that if at any time one of the masters sets in
their mind to not play by the selection rules, and makes an attempt to dominate
completely, the other
masters must each, out of pure self-interest, counteract this attempt at
singular domination, or they risk losing their power altogether, because their
highest achievable ambition within this dynamic is to ensure that they are
selected on the next round. (Taken to an extreme: the only non-genocidal
solution to the existence of psychopaths is to engineer a society that
benefits from their selfishness &amp;ndash; one such solution is to pit them
against &lt;em&gt;each other&lt;/em&gt; in a competition whose rules are such that its
side-effects are beneficial to the group as a whole.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ironically, here the collective yields more power than they would in a
non-hierarchical dynamic: This is how peasants keep their masters hostage.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/books/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s something about learning from a physical object that makes things
&amp;ldquo;click&amp;rdquo; better in my head (it has volume, texture; a particular smell); and I
doubt I&amp;rsquo;m an oddity in this respect &amp;ndash; the root of this effect may be
biological: For example, when recalling some piece of information, often I can
remember where &amp;ndash; within some textbook I read half a decade ago &amp;ndash; the subject
is explained. And I do mean, a literal, &lt;em&gt;physical&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ldquo;where&amp;rdquo;: a page, (a
&lt;em&gt;thing&lt;/em&gt;,) which at all times can be found tucked somewhere within a physical
stack of bound paper, which I can touch and feel; I might even remember where I
was sitting (or standing, or lying), as I held that particular book, open at
that page, when I studied the subject, and what it felt like to the touch, and
how the lighting in the room fell on the paper; maybe I jotted some note on the
margin, maybe I spilled tea on the pages before, giving that &amp;ldquo;where&amp;rdquo; its own
unique irregular texture and color &amp;ndash; all of which my brain will forever
associate with that information. Digital can&amp;rsquo;t do any of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this sense, there is nothing left to improve about the physical book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, if once I open this book I find myself confused, (maybe
because the book was written by a guy named named Spivak, who does not like to
explain what happens in between those little &amp;ldquo;=&amp;rdquo; symbols,) I can&amp;rsquo;t press on
anything and expect it to expand magically and reveal more detail. It&amp;rsquo;s at this
point that I will turn to my laptop, and search for more information, maybe
even ask a stranger half a world away, or watch an interactive video. My copy
of &amp;ldquo;Calculus on Manifolds&amp;rdquo; can&amp;rsquo;t do any of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So even though ebooks do offer some perks, in many ways the printed book
remains superior. &lt;a
href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2015/09/23/business/media/the-plot-twist-e-book-sales-slip-and-print-is-far-from-dead.html&#34;&gt;I
think it&amp;rsquo;s a safe bet that books aren&amp;rsquo;t going anywhere&lt;/a&gt;. Radio did not
replace print, TV did not replace radio. (Interactive did not replace passive;
print did not replace the spoken word.) Each of these media is better suited
for different tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I also still find that the best way to solve a problem (even a programming
problem), is with pen and paper. Physically jotting down an idea beats pressing
buttons while staring at an obnoxious, headache-inducing glowing screen any
time (which I try to avoid as much as possible, even as a software developer).
To me flipping pages still beats searching and clicking &amp;ndash; what a dreadful user
experience is a digital textbook!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://noamswebsite.com/img/quijote.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stones</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/stones/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/stones/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was at the lake last Summer. I picked a mossy old bench to sit, when a group
of adolescents gathered to throw stones into the water.  For an hour they busied
around, making loud gestures and arguing over whose stone made the bigger
splash.  They would try every angle, and then bicker about which one spattered
out the widest, or which one sent the water flying the highest, and how could
they agree on what they&amp;rsquo;d seen if in a moment it was gone? Finally they
approached me hoping I would settle their dispute, but I&amp;rsquo;d not seen the water
splash&amp;ndash; they scoffed, frustrated, and went on their way, and I was free to
continue watching the ripples that now adorned the surface of the lake.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>