<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rs on Noam&#39;s Website About Software</title>
    <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rs on Noam&#39;s Website About Software</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://noamswebsite.com/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweep</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/sweep/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/sweep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was on my regular afternoon bike ride when I noticed a crowd of people
sweeping the walkways. I leaned my bike on a tree and  went to the first man and
asked &amp;ldquo;Why do you sweep?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I sweep because I resign,&amp;rdquo; he said to me.&amp;ldquo;I used to go blue in the face with
how dirty these streets were. But it was no use, they paid no attention, and I
would go mad each day when upon arriving I would dirty my carpet. I swear I was
losing my mind. I would shout and complain and nobody did a damn thing. Finally
I resigned to the situation. And I was struck by a notion, that only one thing
was within my reach to do, and I got myself this broom and since then I keep my
head down and sweep.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;And what if another walks on your path and muddies it again?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Then I sweep.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thanked the man and went on to the next one and asked &amp;ldquo;Why do you sweep?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I sweep because someone has to. I always suspected these streets were not as
clean as they could be, but none would have it,&amp;rdquo; he answered, then looked both
ways to check if anyone was eavesdropping before adding &amp;ldquo;downright dirty,
actually &amp;ndash; and then one day I saw that man over there sweeping. So I got a
broom and started sweeping too.&amp;rdquo; He paused for a moment, tired, then looked at
me again with pride: &amp;ldquo;Look how clean my walkway is!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving on, I asked another group of people, further down the crowd why they
swept: &amp;ldquo;Well, we sweep because it&amp;rsquo;s proper,&amp;rdquo; answered one. &amp;ldquo;We saw those over
there doing it, and it seemed like a good enough thing to do to join in. The
streets are much cleaner now, don&amp;rsquo;t you see?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked further into the crowd, some were sweeping more vigorously than others,
but even the lazy ones stood with brooms in their hands and talked of how much
they loved to sweep, and again I asked one &amp;ldquo;Why do you sweep?&amp;rdquo; and he said &amp;ldquo;We
sweep because everyone sweeps. How else do you think these streets would stay so
clean?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And a little further down, I asked again and one said to me simply &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;ve always
swept.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At last I was lost in the crowd completely, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t make out my bike or the
tree in the distance at all. I looked around me and tapped one of the sweeping
men on the shoulder.  &amp;ldquo;Why do you sweep?&amp;rdquo; I asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a moment he looked at me as if I was strange, then he paused, and a look of
worry came to his face &amp;ndash; it was as if he&amp;rsquo;d not even realized he had been
sweeping all this time! The mere question had snapped him out of a trance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then he was struck by a notion.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Completely</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/completely/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/completely/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I die, I hope it&amp;rsquo;s completely.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creative</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/creative/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/creative/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Is it courage to, or incapacity not-to?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creative person has the courage to experience opposites of his nature and to attempt some reconciliation of them in an individuated expression of himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash;  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.brainpickings.org/2016/12/29/the-creative-architect/&#34;&gt;The Creative Architect&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Enemy Of Your Enemy</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/enemy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/enemy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the enemy of your enemy is your friend, then by the transitive property, if any of your enemies are enemies, you are your enemy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unless the friend of your enemy is not your enemy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stones</title>
      <link>http://noamswebsite.com/r/stones/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://noamswebsite.com/r/stones/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was at the lake last Summer. I picked a mossy old bench to sit, when a group
of adolescents gathered to throw stones into the water.  For an hour they busied
around, making loud gestures and arguing over whose stone made the bigger
splash.  They would try every angle, and then bicker about which one spattered
out the widest, or which one sent the water flying the highest, and how could
they agree on what they&amp;rsquo;d seen if in a moment it was gone? Finally they
approached me hoping I would settle their dispute, but I&amp;rsquo;d not seen the water
splash&amp;ndash; they scoffed, frustrated, and went on their way, and I was free to
continue watching the ripples that now adorned the surface of the lake.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>